<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fly-Tying on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/fly-tying/</link><description>Recent content in Fly-Tying on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:10 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/fly-tying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering the Basics: Essential Fly Tying Techniques for Beginners</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we embark on our journey into the world of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to establish a solid foundation. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re crafting classic patterns or adapting to seasonal changes, mastering the basics can significantly enhance our success on the water. In this roundup, we explore some of the most accessible flies for beginners and the nuanced techniques that can elevate our tying game. By synthesizing insights from Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; and Midcurrent&amp;rsquo;s Tying Tuesday series, we aim to equip novice tiers with the knowledge to confidently tackle their first creations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Vise: Essential Fly Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the art of fly tying, it’s clear that this craft is not only about the patterns we create but also the techniques we employ to bring our creations to life. From the foundational classics highlighted by Bob Reece to the technical nuances needed for winter fishing, there’s a wealth of knowledge available to all levels of tiers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these articles provide valuable insights that can elevate our fly tying game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Essential Patterns Every Angler Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we take a deep dive into the fundamentals of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few foundational patterns can unlock a world of fishing success. From Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s insights in &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers,&amp;rsquo; we learn that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just go-to flies; they are stepping stones to understanding the craft. Each of these flies encapsulates essential techniques that every aspiring tier should grasp, laying the groundwork for more complex creations down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Fly Tying: Essential Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we immerse ourselves in the essential craft of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few key patterns can lay a solid foundation for our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the vice or looking to refine your skills, articles like Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; remind us that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just staples; they are stepping stones into the broader world of fly tying. These flies offer us the chance to practice crucial techniques, from tying stability to creating lifelike movements in the water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roadkill Streamers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:05:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</guid><description>If you want to target hefty trout, forget the small stuff—streamers are your ticket to tight lines, accounting for a staggering 42% of four-pound fish caught in Livingston, Montana. Patterns like Woolly Buggers and Bitch Creeks can dominate in fast water, especially when you employ a slow, deliberate retrieve to mimic injured prey. Don’t miss the chance to amp up your streamer game and hook into those rising fish; the water’s waiting for your next cast!</description></item><item><title>Mallard spey tubes</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-mallard-spey-tubes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-mallard-spey-tubes/</guid><description>Read more about Mallard spey tubes.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: Build Your Skills, One Pattern at a Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that the right fly can mean the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. This roundup dives deep into the art of fly tying, an essential skill that not only enhances our angling arsenal but also connects us to the craft in a meaningful way. From novice tiers sharing their first attempts to experienced anglers revisiting the vice after decades, the journey of fly tying is as diverse as the waters we fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>