<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fly-Tying on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/fly-tying/</link><description>Recent content in Fly-Tying on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:07:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/fly-tying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Tying It All Together: Innovative Techniques to Up Your Fly Game</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-exploring-unique-fly-tying-techniques-from-spey-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:07:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-exploring-unique-fly-tying-techniques-from-spey-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fly tying isn&amp;rsquo;t just about slapping some feathers onto a hook; it&amp;rsquo;s an art form that combines both tradition and innovation. From the classic Woolly Bugger to the modern marvels like Mallard spey tubes, there&amp;rsquo;s a world of techniques just waiting to enhance your fishing game. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a newbie trying to understand the ropes or a seasoned tyer looking to spice things up, the insights from the latest articles on fly tying offer something for everyone. For instance, take Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s piece on foundational flies — the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis. These are the building blocks that any angler should master before they start diving into the more complex stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Where Creativity Meets the Water: The Artistic Side of Fly Tying</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-03-the-crossroads-of-art-and-fly-tying-creative-inspi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-03-the-crossroads-of-art-and-fly-tying-creative-inspi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I sit on the banks of the Deschutes, fly rod in hand and the sun dipping low, I can’t help but notice how much fly tying has become an art form in its own right. It’s not just about matching the hatch anymore; it’s about expressing yourself with every feather and thread you wrap around that hook. This theme of blending creativity with technique really shines through in recent articles. Take Duane Hada&amp;rsquo;s tribute mural for the legendary Dave Whitlock, which reminds us that the stories behind our flies are just as important as the flies themselves. His mural isn’t just paint; it’s a homage that pulls the entire community together, anchoring our passion in a shared history.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Classics: Essential Fly Patterns Every New Tyer Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-the-art-of-tying-classic-patterns-for-new-fly-tyer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-the-art-of-tying-classic-patterns-for-new-fly-tyer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest: when it comes to fly tying, the foundation you build is as crucial as the fish you hope to catch. I’ve spent countless hours behind the vise, and trust me, it’s those classic patterns that keep my box stocked and my fishing trips successful. Bob Reece from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline hits the nail on the head by outlining three must-have flies for newbies: the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis. These aren’t just pretty feathers—each of these patterns teaches essential techniques that lay the groundwork for more advanced tying. If you can master these, you’re well on your way to becoming a competent tyer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fly Tying Fundamentals: Mastering Seasonal Patterns for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the essentials of fly tying, we recognize that the art is not just about creativity—it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the rhythms of nature and how our patterns can mimic them. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a novice just starting out or an experienced tyer looking to refine your skills, the three classic flies highlighted by Bob Reece—Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis—serve as foundational tools in our fly boxes. These patterns don’t just represent the basics; they embody the versatility and adaptability required across seasons and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fly Tying 101: Your Essential Guide to Building a Solid Fly Box</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-getting-started-with-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-getting-started-with-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve decided to dip your toe into the world of fly tying? Welcome to the club, where every knot has a story and every thread has a purpose. It can feel a bit overwhelming at first, but trust me, the satisfaction of seeing a fish take a fly you’ve painstakingly crafted is unmatched. I’ve scoured the waters of various articles to strip away the fluff and get down to the brass tacks of what you really need to know as you start your fly tying journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Patterns That Hook Fish</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we delve into the world of fly tying, it’s clear that mastering a few essential patterns can significantly enhance our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting or looking to refine your skills, understanding the foundational techniques behind classic flies is crucial. Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s article on Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline highlights three timeless patterns—the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis—that not only build our skills but also stand the test of time on the water. Each of these flies offers unique advantages and teaches valuable tying techniques that serve as a springboard for more complex patterns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Basics: Essential Fly Tying Techniques for Beginners</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we embark on our journey into the world of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to establish a solid foundation. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re crafting classic patterns or adapting to seasonal changes, mastering the basics can significantly enhance our success on the water. In this roundup, we explore some of the most accessible flies for beginners and the nuanced techniques that can elevate our tying game. By synthesizing insights from Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; and Midcurrent&amp;rsquo;s Tying Tuesday series, we aim to equip novice tiers with the knowledge to confidently tackle their first creations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Vise: Essential Fly Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the art of fly tying, it’s clear that this craft is not only about the patterns we create but also the techniques we employ to bring our creations to life. From the foundational classics highlighted by Bob Reece to the technical nuances needed for winter fishing, there’s a wealth of knowledge available to all levels of tiers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these articles provide valuable insights that can elevate our fly tying game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Essential Patterns Every Angler Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we take a deep dive into the fundamentals of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few foundational patterns can unlock a world of fishing success. From Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s insights in &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers,&amp;rsquo; we learn that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just go-to flies; they are stepping stones to understanding the craft. Each of these flies encapsulates essential techniques that every aspiring tier should grasp, laying the groundwork for more complex creations down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Fly Tying: Essential Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we immerse ourselves in the essential craft of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few key patterns can lay a solid foundation for our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the vice or looking to refine your skills, articles like Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; remind us that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just staples; they are stepping stones into the broader world of fly tying. These flies offer us the chance to practice crucial techniques, from tying stability to creating lifelike movements in the water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roadkill Streamers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:05:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</guid><description>If you want to target hefty trout, forget the small stuff—streamers are your ticket to tight lines, accounting for a staggering 42% of four-pound fish caught in Livingston, Montana. Patterns like Woolly Buggers and Bitch Creeks can dominate in fast water, especially when you employ a slow, deliberate retrieve to mimic injured prey. Don’t miss the chance to amp up your streamer game and hook into those rising fish; the water’s waiting for your next cast!</description></item><item><title>Mallard spey tubes</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-mallard-spey-tubes/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 06:43:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-mallard-spey-tubes/</guid><description>Read more about Mallard spey tubes.</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: Build Your Skills, One Pattern at a Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that the right fly can mean the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. This roundup dives deep into the art of fly tying, an essential skill that not only enhances our angling arsenal but also connects us to the craft in a meaningful way. From novice tiers sharing their first attempts to experienced anglers revisiting the vice after decades, the journey of fly tying is as diverse as the waters we fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>