<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Freshwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/freshwater/</link><description>Recent content in Freshwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/freshwater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating the Waters of Trout Conservation: New Regulations and Their Impact</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-trout-conservation-navigating-new-regulations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-trout-conservation-navigating-new-regulations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers passionate about trout fishing, we understand the fine balance between enjoying our sport and ensuring the sustainability of trout populations. Recent articles shed light on critical developments in trout conservation efforts across the U.S., particularly with new regulations in Arkansas and the precarious status of the Skagit steelhead season. These changes not only affect our fishing practices but also require us to rethink our approach to conservation at large.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Aquatic Heritage</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:12:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers and stewards of our waterways, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial that we stay informed and engaged with the pressing conservation issues affecting our favorite fishing spots. From the new regulations in Arkansas aimed at reviving trout populations to the looming threat of industrial mining in Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s pristine Boundary Waters, the conversation around conservation has never been more urgent. These issues are not isolated; they are interconnected and reflect broader challenges we face in protecting our ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Change: Navigating Conservation Challenges in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that our passion for fishing is deeply intertwined with the health of our ecosystems. Recent developments across various regions remind us that while we cast our lines, we must also cast our voices in support of conservation efforts. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at recovering trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, the fishing landscape is at a critical juncture. Each of these stories illustrates the complexities of balancing our love for the sport with the urgent need to protect our freshwater resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Waters and Fisheries</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we are not just participants in a sport; we are stewards of our waters. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight pressing conservation issues across various regions, reminding us that our fishing experiences are deeply intertwined with the health of aquatic ecosystems. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at revitalizing trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that the fight for our fisheries is both complex and critical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Tomorrow: The Crucial Role of Conservation in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As passionate anglers, we know that our sport is inseparable from the health of our ecosystems. Recent articles highlight a growing awareness of conservation issues that directly impact our fishing experiences and the future of fish populations. From Arkansas&amp;rsquo; new trout regulations in the wake of a hatchery crisis to the alarming potential threats facing Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s Boundary Waters, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we must prioritize conservation efforts like never before. These discussions are not just policy debates; they are calls to action for us as stewards of the waters we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Caddisfly</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-caddisfly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:26:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-caddisfly/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/5pj8ot7ztlfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Duane Hada Paints Memorial Mural Honoring Fly-Fishing Icon Dave Whitlock</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:28:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</guid><description>Renowned Ozark artist Duane Hada is painting a memorial tribute to Dave Whitlock, the Oklahoma-born fly-fishing legend who spent more than four decades on the White River and whose innovations—from the ubiquitous Dave&amp;rsquo;s Hopper to the Whitlock-Vibert Box egg incubator system—helped establish north&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Some pheasant tails I tied up.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-some-pheasant-tails-i-tied-up/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:16:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-some-pheasant-tails-i-tied-up/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/ei8umnhjhlfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Arkansas Implements New Trout Regulations Following Historic Hatchery Crisis</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</guid><description>The new rules, effective February 1, 2026, replace the emergency catch-and-release orders enacted in October 2025 and signal cautious optimism that the White River system can sustain limited harvest while its fish populations recover.</description></item><item><title>New to streamers! lmk on opinions</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-new-to-streamers-lmk-on-opinions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-new-to-streamers-lmk-on-opinions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qmywpx"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is this a rainbow?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-this-a-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:13:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-this-a-rainbow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/4bdukvxevkfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/troutfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A streamer a day keeps the cold away!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-a-streamer-a-day-keeps-the-cold-away/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-a-streamer-a-day-keeps-the-cold-away/</guid><description>Hackle, flash, reverse tied craft fur coming in hot!</description></item><item><title>One of my biggest accomplishments yet</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</guid><description>One of my biggest accomplishments so far, the California heritage trout challenge. Fort the first trout, I went up to the Tahoe area to catch the Lahontan cutthrot trout.</description></item><item><title>Not sure what this is</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-not-sure-what-this-is/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:18:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-not-sure-what-this-is/</guid><description>Too small for a Golden Stonefli? Too big for a Cadhis? 1&amp;quot; long. Two.materials. Elk hair and a hackle feather bmp (bottom mounted parachute). No name yet. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s a Short Rib?</description></item><item><title>White soft hackled caddis</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-white-soft-hackled-caddis/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:48:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-white-soft-hackled-caddis/</guid><description>Inspired by the snow in New England</description></item><item><title>The Fragile Ecosystem: Conservation Challenges Facing Fly Fishing Today</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we revel in the thrill of casting our lines into pristine waters, yet we must remain vigilant about the environmental challenges that threaten our beloved sport. Recent articles shed light on pressing conservation issues, from the alarming &amp;lsquo;snow drought&amp;rsquo; affecting Western rivers to the bureaucratic hurdles endangering the iconic Skagit River steelhead season. These challenges not only impact our fishing experiences but also the health of our aquatic ecosystems and the future of fish populations we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Protecting Our Waters: A Call to Action for Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-conservation-concerns-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-conservation-concerns-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, our connection to the water goes beyond the simple joy of casting a line; it is intertwined with our responsibility to protect the ecosystems that sustain our favorite species. Recent discussions around conservation issues shed light on the critical challenges facing freshwater habitats and the fish that inhabit them. From the potential threat of industrial mining in the Boundary Waters to the uncertain future of the Skagit River’s steelhead season, the implications of these developments reach far beyond local waters. We must recognize that the health of our fisheries is inextricably linked to the political and environmental decisions made today.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trout Tactics: Mastering the Art and Science of Freshwater Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of trout fishing, we recognize that the pursuit of these elusive fish goes far beyond simply casting a line. From experimenting with unconventional bait, as seen in the Reddit post where a wacky rigged trout worm led to a successful catch, to understanding the body language of aggressive trout in fall, our journey is filled with insights that can elevate our angling game. We’re not just fishing; we’re learning to communicate with the fish in their own language—be it through the right flies or the perfect presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>No winter storm in NM</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</guid><description>Hand tied small streamer deaddrifted under indicator tore up. Stockers.</description></item><item><title>Nice stocked Rainbow</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</guid><description>Was throwing lures all morning with no follows or hits. Tried something a bit unconventional and was able to hook into this one with two trout worms wacky rigged on a trout magnet jig under a bobber. Close to 15 inches.</description></item><item><title>First fly since 1993, and it's ugly.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</guid><description>Got bored and had access to a while bunch of fly tying supplies. Figured I should likely have a concept of it being the local fly club president. haven&amp;rsquo;t tied a fly since 1993 at the Scout jamboree. seems to have turned out fine, not sure if it would survive a cast. Not sure what it&amp;rsquo;s for.</description></item><item><title>Tj Hooker</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-tj-hooker/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:06:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-tj-hooker/</guid><description>Hook: Core Jig hook size 8 Thread: TheFlySmith 74D nylon Tail: Wooly bugger marabou Body: Antron bugger chenille Legs: Fulling mill micro barred legs Resin: uv craft Tools: TheFlySmith</description></item><item><title>My personal favorite as it's what I caught my first Atlantic Salmon on</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-personal-favorite-as-it-s-what-i-caught-my-first-atlantic/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 12:35:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-personal-favorite-as-it-s-what-i-caught-my-first-atlantic/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/po46mvtmncfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First ever Rainbow Trout!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-ever-rainbow-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-ever-rainbow-trout/</guid><description>Caught my first rainbow trout ever in a stocked pond in Louisiana! Really cool that LDWF does it for the communities. Beautiful fish and a fun fight, can’t wait to catch more later this year in Colorado.</description></item><item><title>Sea trout muddler</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-sea-trout-muddler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-sea-trout-muddler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/b2potzw23cfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reading The Body Language of Highly Aggressive Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move into the fall months, the use of streamer patterns typically increases for many fly fishers. There are many factors that lead to success when pursuing trout with these beefy creations. Evaluating the body language of the aggressive fish that chase these flies can improve your odds of hooking up.</description></item><item><title>Never seen one like this.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-never-seen-one-like-this/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-never-seen-one-like-this/</guid><description>My little brother caught this trout at Lake Siskiyou, CA. Is this a rainbow?</description></item><item><title>First 2 of the year</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-first-2-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-first-2-of-the-year/</guid><description>Located in Ohio, and although I have been trying, I haven’t been able to catch anything since New Year’s Eve. Today I decided to ditch work early, and hit the trout honey hole. No keepers, but was happy to end my drought, and get my first of the year.</description></item><item><title>Stocked rainbow. Learning to use kastmasters and spoons more.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-stocked-rainbow-learning-to-use-kastmasters-and-spoons-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:16:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-stocked-rainbow-learning-to-use-kastmasters-and-spoons-more/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/xv57p57q77fg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/troutfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can you help me identify this trout is it wild or stocked</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</guid><description>Caught in bishop Ca catch and release</description></item><item><title>“Snow Drought” Threatening Western Rivers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-snow-drought-threatening-western-rivers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:41:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-snow-drought-threatening-western-rivers/</guid><description>An aptly-named “snow drought” has much of the Western United States in its grasp, threatening water supplies in reservoirs, and flows in many of the country’s favorite trout rivers. A quick glance at the National Weather and Climate Center’s snow-water equivalent map paints a stark picture.</description></item><item><title>New Spinners I've Always Wanted To Try.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-new-spinners-i-ve-always-wanted-to-try/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-new-spinners-i-ve-always-wanted-to-try/</guid><description>I have high hopes for these and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see if they will contend against Mepps, Panther Martin, and Rooster Tails. I will be targeting stocked trout, so it should be fun.</description></item><item><title>Another “tico” trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-another-tico-trout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:53:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-another-tico-trout/</guid><description>One of the few “big” trouts we have here in Costa Rica, it’s not that common to find them this size</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Some wild Utah cutthroat</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-some-wild-utah-cutthroat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:47:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-some-wild-utah-cutthroat/</guid><description>My first fish of the new year, I had never thrown my bladed jigs for trout for some reason and decided to try it out. I went to hit my favorite spot and discovered that it was now posted no trespassing.</description></item><item><title>Minnesota’s Boundary Water Canoe Area Wilderness on the Chopping Block After House Republicans’ Vote</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-minnesota-s-boundary-water-canoe-area-wilderness-on-the-chop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 02:15:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-minnesota-s-boundary-water-canoe-area-wilderness-on-the-chop/</guid><description>The Boundary Waters Canoe Area Wilderness, located in Northeast Minnesota, is a national treasure but is once again threatened by Congressional action to permit industrial mining activities.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>Snake River Dams Litigation Resumes After Trump Administration Revokes Biden-Era Agreement</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-snake-river-dams-litigation-resumes-after-trump-administrati/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:57:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-snake-river-dams-litigation-resumes-after-trump-administrati/</guid><description>One of the most consequential rulings for Pacific Northwest salmon and steelhead in years.</description></item><item><title>Skagit River Steelhead Season Not Likely To Open</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-skagit-river-steelhead-season-not-likely-to-open/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-skagit-river-steelhead-season-not-likely-to-open/</guid><description>The late winter and early spring catch-and-release season on the famed Skagit River may not happen in 2026, and not because of too few wild steelhead returning to the river. In fact, the numbers support a limited catch-and-release fishery with no retention of wild fish allowed.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Essential Winter Midges and Technical Nymphs</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</guid><description>When winter temperatures settle in, trout slow down—and so must our approach. Success demands technical midge patterns and refined subsurface presentations that can fool even the most lethargic fish.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>Skagit Steelhead Season Hangs by a Thread—Not for Lack of Fish, But Funding</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</guid><description>As of mid-January, the highly anticipated catch-and-release season on Washington&amp;rsquo;s Skagit and Sauk rivers—a bucket-list destination for steelhead anglers across the Pacific Northwest—stands on the verge of cancellation. The culprit isn&amp;rsquo;t biology. It&amp;rsquo;s bureaucracy.</description></item><item><title>Sage Unveils Limited Edition Enforcer Grand Slam Reels: A Collector’s Dream for Flats Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</guid><description>The three-model collection pays tribute to the legendary saltwater &amp;ldquo;Grand Slam&amp;rdquo;—the rare feat of landing a bonefish, permit, and tarpon in a single day.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Patterns Worth Your Vise Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</guid><description>From micro-midges to bright worms, the range here reflects the reality of cold-water fishing: you need options.</description></item><item><title>How to get started in trout Spey with Pete Kutzer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</guid><description>Any kind of two-handed fishing is confusing for those of us who mostly fish with a single-handed rod. I asked the great Pete Kutzer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Golden Trout, with Jessica Strickland</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:04:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</guid><description>Jessica Strickland [38:07]is Trout Unlimited&amp;rsquo;s California Inland Trout director and is an expert on the historical and curent range&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Trout, Tarpon, and Other Critters in Costa Rica, with Kevin Jackson</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</guid><description>Did you know you can catch trout and tarpon in the same trip, along with exotic jungle species? I didn&amp;rsquo;t either, but Kevin Jackson [42:22] of Fly Fish Costa Rica shares&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>