<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Steelhead on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/steelhead/</link><description>Recent content in Steelhead on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:27:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/steelhead/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Skagit Steelhead Saga: Where Conservation Meets Opportunity</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-skagit-steelhead-saga-conservation-and-fishing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:27:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-skagit-steelhead-saga-conservation-and-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;The Skagit River is a crown jewel for steelhead anglers, renowned for its stunning scenery and the thrill of catching those elusive fish. Yet, as I navigate the complexities of this river’s future, I can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel a deep sense of urgency. Recent articles from Fly Lords and Midcurrent highlight a disheartening irony: we’re not facing a biological crisis for steelhead, but rather a bureaucratic one. The potential cancellation of the catch-and-release season isn’t due to a lack of fish returning, but rather a lack of funding and support.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Conservation: The Urgent Challenges Facing Our Waters</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:31:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we often find ourselves lost in the thrill of the chase, whether it’s the flash of a trout rising to a dry fly or a steelhead tearing through the current. However, beneath the surface of our beloved waters, a more complex and pressing narrative unfolds—one that threatens the very species we seek to catch. Recent developments in conservation policy illustrate that while we celebrate our sport, we must also confront the realities of a changing environment and the bureaucratic hurdles that impede effective conservation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>