<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Travel on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/travel/</link><description>Recent content in Travel on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 01:53:11 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/travel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>California Road Trip Advice?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-california-road-trip-advice/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 01:53:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-california-road-trip-advice/</guid><description>Hey everyone!I’m heading to the Bay Area for a work trip in late March and I’ve cleared my schedule for several days afterward to squeeze in some fly fishing.</description></item><item><title>2026 F3T Behind the Lens: Black Sheep</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-black-sheep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 21:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-black-sheep/</guid><description>Jako Lucas is no stranger to the Fly Fishing Film Tour, nor far-off, stoke-filled destination fishing adventures. For this installment of F3T Behind the Lens, we sat down with the team behind Black Sheep: Jako Lucas of CaptainJack Productions and Wade Kelly of Flow State Productions.</description></item><item><title>Seeking a Tarpon Guide - Destin FL</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</guid><description>I’ll be in the Destin, FL area this June and would love the chance to target tarpon on the fly. So far, I’ve only found one charter that specifically offers tarpon fly fishing trips.</description></item><item><title>Some Spey flies for an upcoming trip</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-some-spey-flies-for-an-upcoming-trip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:07:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-some-spey-flies-for-an-upcoming-trip/</guid><description>Top two: HeggeliMiddle: Anderson’s euphoriaBottom: Andersons (blue variant)</description></item><item><title>Fly Fisherman - April/May 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-fly-fisherman-april-may-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:42:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-fly-fisherman-april-may-2026/</guid><description>Fly Fisherman is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading magazine for fly fishing. Every issue provides expert advice on the latest fly fishing techniques, the newest tackle and the hottest new fly patterns. Through informative articles, it highlights the best destinations for t…</description></item><item><title>Best value saltwater fishing for ≈5k?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-best-value-saltwater-fishing-for-5k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-best-value-saltwater-fishing-for-5k/</guid><description>Planning a trip this spring/summer and trying to figure out the best bang for my buck.</description></item><item><title>8 or 9wt as a second rod? Would you recommend the Fenwick HMG?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-8-or-9wt-as-a-second-rod-would-you-recommend-the-fenwick-hmg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:34:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-8-or-9wt-as-a-second-rod-would-you-recommend-the-fenwick-hmg/</guid><description>Hi everyone,I’m actively shopping for a second fly fishing rod in anticipation of next season. I currently have a 5wt setup that I bought last year to target trout and smallies.I’m looking for a second setup to complement it and I’m wondering if I should go with a 8wt or 9wt.</description></item><item><title>Traveling with Waders/Boots</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-traveling-with-waders-boots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 02:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-traveling-with-waders-boots/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never flown for a fly fishing trip, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be flying out to PA this spring and plan on getting some fishing in. How are people traveling with waders/boots? I see tons of options for transporting rods/reels, but less specific options for traveling with waders and boots.</description></item><item><title>Newbie needs advice</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-newbie-needs-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 01:45:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-newbie-needs-advice/</guid><description>Me and a buddy who are relatively new to the fly fishing world are planning a trip to the snake and Missouri rivers around late June and need some advice.</description></item><item><title>Follow up on Montenegro trip</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-follow-up-on-montenegro-trip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 20:50:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-follow-up-on-montenegro-trip/</guid><description>I recently came on here and asked if anyone knew any European Taimen (Huchen) guides in Montenegro, and I followed up on the one lead and made the trip to the small town of Plav, where I met my great guide, Oki, who showed me around the Lim River.</description></item><item><title>West Branch of the Ausable</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-west-branch-of-the-ausable/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:14:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-west-branch-of-the-ausable/</guid><description>I’m planning a trip the second weekend of June to the Wilmington, New York area to fish the West branch of the Ausable with a buddy. We’re staying at the hungry trout, which seems like a good affordable option close to the water.I’m curious if anyone can share any tips or hints for the areanotrelated to fishing.</description></item><item><title>Chile 🇨🇱 brown trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-chile-brown-trout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-chile-brown-trout/</guid><description>Just a few highlights from a great couple of days fishing in the south of Chile! I’ve been in Santiago for a couple of months while I’m studying abroad and knew I had to make the trip down south while I had a good chance. Definitely don’t regret it.</description></item><item><title>Need some help</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-need-some-help/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:23:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-need-some-help/</guid><description>I don’t really know what I’m doing yet. I’m going backpacking with friends and we’re planning to try and catch trout. I’m thinking about getting the Daiwa Megaforce Travel Rod 2.10 m because it folds down small enough to fit in my backpack.I’d like to invest in decent gear without breaking the bank, but I’m confused about line sizes.</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Fall, What You Should Know About Sinking Fly Lines</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</guid><description>By Garner Reid A GOOD PORTION OF MY FLY FISHING INVOLVES THROWING SOME SORT OF A SINKING FLY LINE. Realistically, half of my time on the water involves streamers and sinking lines at least for some part of the day. If I am not out on the water guiding for streamer-eating fish like stripers, I’m in the fly shop talking about them.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Streamers, Nymphs, and Innovative Emergers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-tying-tuesday-streamers-nymphs-and-innovative-emergers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-tying-tuesday-streamers-nymphs-and-innovative-emergers/</guid><description>From the streamer junkie stripping heavy articulated meat to the technical purist, there’s something here to keep your hands busy and your mind on the water. So heat up the coffee, fire up the UV lamp, and put a few new tools in the box before spring arrives.</description></item><item><title>Wanderlust on the Water: Unveiling the World's Hidden Fly Fishing Gems</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-traveling-the-world-unique-fly-fishing-destination/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-traveling-the-world-unique-fly-fishing-destination/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the sun rises on another day of casting lines, the thrill of discovering new fishing destinations pulses through my veins like the salty air of the Florida Keys. Whether it’s the allure of Mongolia’s untamed wilderness, the breathtaking heights of the Alps, or the vibrant jungles of Costa Rica, each location beckons with the promise of adventure and diversity in species. It’s time to pack your gear and shake off the familiar, as I dive into some of the most unique fly fishing spots around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater Newbie to Saltwater Sage: Navigating the Flats</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:06:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every saltwater angler can recall the moment when they first stepped onto the glistening flats, the sun warming their shoulders and the smell of the ocean mingling with the adrenaline of the chase. Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing can feel like stepping into a different world, and it’s a journey that’s both daunting and exhilarating. Whether you’re a newbie casting for the first time, like the enthusiastic angler who recently shared their experience in La Paz, or you&amp;rsquo;re gearing up with a trusty 9-foot rod and chartreuse fly, the saltwater bug is contagious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saltwater Fly Fishing: From the Flats to the Deep Blue</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that this realm offers a diverse tapestry of adventures, techniques, and gear. From the bustling flats teeming with bonefish and permit to the vast blue waters where mighty tarpon roam, our experiences remind us that every angler can find their niche in the salt. A recent Reddit post highlighted the thrill of a first-time outing in La Paz, where the excitement of live bait and fast retrieves turned a casual day into a memorable adventure. Similarly, tales of epic tarpon days in Costa Rica serve as a testament to the sheer adrenaline and joy these fish can bring to our lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Duane Hada Paints Memorial Mural Honoring Fly-Fishing Icon Dave Whitlock</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:28:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</guid><description>Renowned Ozark artist Duane Hada is painting a memorial tribute to Dave Whitlock, the Oklahoma-born fly-fishing legend who spent more than four decades on the White River and whose innovations—from the ubiquitous Dave&amp;rsquo;s Hopper to the Whitlock-Vibert Box egg incubator system—helped establish north&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Skagit Steelhead Season Hangs by a Thread—Not for Lack of Fish, But Funding</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</guid><description>As of mid-January, the highly anticipated catch-and-release season on Washington&amp;rsquo;s Skagit and Sauk rivers—a bucket-list destination for steelhead anglers across the Pacific Northwest—stands on the verge of cancellation. The culprit isn&amp;rsquo;t biology. It&amp;rsquo;s bureaucracy.</description></item><item><title>Meet the Nominees for the 2025 Orvis-Endorsed Awards!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2025-03-03-meet-the-nominees-for-the-2025-orvis-endorsed-awards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:49:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2025-03-03-meet-the-nominees-for-the-2025-orvis-endorsed-awards/</guid><description>2025 marks the 40th year that the Orvis Company will recognize excellence in sporting experiences through its Endorsed Lodges, Outfitters, and Guides (ELOG) program. The winners of this year’s coveted “Of the Year” Awards will be announced virtually via blog and social posts on March 26th. Here are this year’s nominees . .</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Alps, with Miha Ivanc</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-19-fishing-the-alps-with-miha-ivanc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-19-fishing-the-alps-with-miha-ivanc/</guid><description>I frequently get questions from listeners traveling to Europe, curious about fly fishing opportunities in Italy, France, Austria, and Switzerland. I&amp;rsquo;ve never fished there&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>