<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techniques on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Techniques on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Strategies for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we navigate the diverse seasons of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to adapt our techniques to the ever-changing behaviors of these spirited fish. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall to the subtle nuances of spring creeks, understanding the seasonal dynamics can significantly enhance our angling success. In this roundup, we draw insights from various articles that highlight pivotal strategies for each season, ensuring we&amp;rsquo;re well-equipped to tackle trout no matter the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Basics: Essential Fly Tying Techniques for Beginners</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we embark on our journey into the world of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to establish a solid foundation. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re crafting classic patterns or adapting to seasonal changes, mastering the basics can significantly enhance our success on the water. In this roundup, we explore some of the most accessible flies for beginners and the nuanced techniques that can elevate our tying game. By synthesizing insights from Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; and Midcurrent&amp;rsquo;s Tying Tuesday series, we aim to equip novice tiers with the knowledge to confidently tackle their first creations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamer Presentation: The Key to Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, the nuances of presentation can make all the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in various discussions—from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline’s insights on the art of streamer movement to Reddit’s lively exchanges about effective patterns—our approach to how we present our flies can be the game-changer. Whether we’re working with articulated patterns or classic sculpin imitations, it’s clear that finesse in our technique is paramount. The water is alive with potential, and it’s our job to entice those fish with the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Techniques for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we journey through the seasons, our approach to trout fishing must evolve alongside the changing conditions. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall trout, as detailed by Bob Reece at Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline, to the vital implications of weather patterns outlined by Fly Lords, we gain a clearer understanding of how to adapt our strategies effectively. We’re reminded that staying attuned to environmental cues not only enhances our success but also deepens our connection to the water we love to fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Vise: Essential Fly Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the art of fly tying, it’s clear that this craft is not only about the patterns we create but also the techniques we employ to bring our creations to life. From the foundational classics highlighted by Bob Reece to the technical nuances needed for winter fishing, there’s a wealth of knowledge available to all levels of tiers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these articles provide valuable insights that can elevate our fly tying game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Strategies for Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of streamer fishing, it becomes evident that success isn’t just a matter of tossing a big fly into the water and hoping for the best. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight a critical theme: the importance of presentation. From the insights shared in Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline about using a long leader and intermediate line to bring your sculpin patterns to life, to the discussion on the deliberate retrieves necessary for patterns like Woolly Buggers, we see that the way our flies behave can make all the difference. Whether we’re fishing in a tailwater or a fast-moving stream, mastering these nuanced techniques can elevate our fishing game substantially.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Essential Patterns Every Angler Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we take a deep dive into the fundamentals of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few foundational patterns can unlock a world of fishing success. From Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s insights in &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers,&amp;rsquo; we learn that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just go-to flies; they are stepping stones to understanding the craft. Each of these flies encapsulates essential techniques that every aspiring tier should grasp, laying the groundwork for more complex creations down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout Techniques: From Seasonal Strategies to Catching Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the world of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that our approach must evolve with the seasons. From the new regulations impacting the White River system to the nuanced techniques required for catching trout during the colder months, we are reminded that adaptability is key to our success on the water. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered showcase not just the challenges we face in maintaining sustainable fish populations, but also the artistry and strategy involved in maximizing our catch rates throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Unleashing the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fly fishing for big trout, mastering the art of streamer presentation is non-negotiable. We’ve gathered insights from seasoned anglers and experts who emphasize that how we present our streamers can make all the difference between a day of empty casts and a net full of trophies. Whether you’re working articulated patterns or classic styles, it’s clear that the magic lies in the dance of the fly through the water. Articles from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline and contributions from the fly-tying community highlight techniques and strategies that can elevate our game, especially as we head into the fall months when trout become more aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is Original Artwork Allowed? Sci-Fi Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</guid><description>My friends told me to share some of my fly fishing related artwork here. I&amp;rsquo;m a local artist in the Helena, MT area and I create Sci-Fi based artwork that sometimes overlaps with fly fishing. Hope you all enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Fishing Streamers Is Still All About Presentation</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</guid><description>Mastering the art of streamer fishing hinges on presentation—something every fly angler can appreciate, whether you’re tossing a hefty articulated pattern or a classic Maine-style streamer. In a recent outing on a prime Tailwater, I found success working snaky sculpins with a long leader and intermediate line, while my friends experimented with a Sex Dungeon and other variations, proving that it&amp;rsquo;s all about how you make that imitation dance through the water. Tight lines and rising fish await those willing to perfect their technique; dive into the full article for tips on maximizing your streamer game!</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Flats: Saltwater Fly Fishing Techniques and Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the flats present both unique challenges and unforgettable rewards. From the adrenaline rush of landing a giant tarpon in Costa Rica to the strategic nuances of targeting bonefish and permit, our exploration of these articles reveals the depth of skill and knowledge required to truly excel in saltwater environments. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned angler or just wading into the world of saltwater fly fishing, there’s a wealth of insights to glean from the experiences shared by fellow anglers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Fly Tying: Essential Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we immerse ourselves in the essential craft of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few key patterns can lay a solid foundation for our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the vice or looking to refine your skills, articles like Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; remind us that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just staples; they are stepping stones into the broader world of fly tying. These flies offer us the chance to practice crucial techniques, from tying stability to creating lifelike movements in the water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Big Ones: A Saltwater Fly Fishing Odyssey</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the pursuit of species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit offers both challenge and thrill. From firsthand accounts of rookie anglers navigating the beaches of La Paz to the latest gear revelations from Sage, we’re reminded that every cast can lead to a story worth telling. This isn’t just about hooking the big one; it’s about the journey we embark on and the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: Build Your Skills, One Pattern at a Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that the right fly can mean the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. This roundup dives deep into the art of fly tying, an essential skill that not only enhances our angling arsenal but also connects us to the craft in a meaningful way. From novice tiers sharing their first attempts to experienced anglers revisiting the vice after decades, the journey of fly tying is as diverse as the waters we fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trout Tactics: Mastering the Art and Science of Freshwater Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of trout fishing, we recognize that the pursuit of these elusive fish goes far beyond simply casting a line. From experimenting with unconventional bait, as seen in the Reddit post where a wacky rigged trout worm led to a successful catch, to understanding the body language of aggressive trout in fall, our journey is filled with insights that can elevate our angling game. We’re not just fishing; we’re learning to communicate with the fish in their own language—be it through the right flies or the perfect presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nice stocked Rainbow</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</guid><description>Was throwing lures all morning with no follows or hits. Tried something a bit unconventional and was able to hook into this one with two trout worms wacky rigged on a trout magnet jig under a bobber. Close to 15 inches.</description></item><item><title>First fly since 1993, and it's ugly.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</guid><description>Got bored and had access to a while bunch of fly tying supplies. Figured I should likely have a concept of it being the local fly club president. haven&amp;rsquo;t tied a fly since 1993 at the Scout jamboree. seems to have turned out fine, not sure if it would survive a cast. Not sure what it&amp;rsquo;s for.</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Fishing Sunglasses (Sanofan Fluid Tint)</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</guid><description>I’ve replied to a couple of posts in this sub with my recommendation for the best fly fishing sunglasses I’ve ever used, so I figure I’d make a post about these. These Sanofan Fluid Tints are not only the best value for money fishing sunnies I’ve ever seen, but just downright the best I’ve ever used (mauis, smiths, etc).</description></item><item><title>Reading The Body Language of Highly Aggressive Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move into the fall months, the use of streamer patterns typically increases for many fly fishers. There are many factors that lead to success when pursuing trout with these beefy creations. Evaluating the body language of the aggressive fish that chase these flies can improve your odds of hooking up.</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>What Current Fly Rods Will Be Collectibles In 20 Years?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</guid><description>Some fly rods end up as more than just another entry in that year’s product catalog. A select few gain a cult following, often retaining their value (and exceeding their original retail price) as the years march on.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Patterns Worth Your Vise Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</guid><description>From micro-midges to bright worms, the range here reflects the reality of cold-water fishing: you need options.</description></item><item><title>How to get started in trout Spey with Pete Kutzer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</guid><description>Any kind of two-handed fishing is confusing for those of us who mostly fish with a single-handed rod. I asked the great Pete Kutzer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: 14 Tips for Spring Creek Fishing, with Brant Oswald</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</guid><description>Brant Oswald [23:20] is a veteran guide, teacher, and fly shop operator with over 40 years in the business&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>So you want a job in the fly-fishing industry? With Kirk Deeter</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</guid><description>I get regular questions from people about getting a job in the fly-fishing industry, both in the podcast mailbox and in person at shows and store visits. It&amp;rsquo;s a tough question and I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers so I called upon my buddy Kirk Deeter&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>North American and European fly-tying cross pollination with Barry Ord Clarke</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 05:32:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</guid><description>Barry Ord Clarke is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular fly tiers, through his books, videos, and web site. Originally from the UK but living in Norway, Barry keeps&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>