<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Techniques on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/techniques/</link><description>Recent content in Techniques on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/techniques/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ugly stik of fly fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-ugly-stik-of-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 05:47:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-ugly-stik-of-fly-fishing/</guid><description>I’m in eastern Idaho and do alot of trout fishing. Growing up I only learned how to spinner fish and we only used ugly stik. What’s the fly fishing equivalent of ugly stik? I want to get into fly fishing but not sure I want to spend so much money. Thanks</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on a Winston Air 2 864</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-thoughts-on-a-winston-air-2-864/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-thoughts-on-a-winston-air-2-864/</guid><description>I want to get a higher end rod, starting with a range I generally fish a lot. A light all around fly rod, sans euro styles. This range suffices a majority of my fishing.it seems Winston stepped out a bit from their dry fly only vibe and the Air 2 looks appealing but I have not spoke with anyone who has fished one.</description></item><item><title>Lil sand eel streamer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-lil-sand-eel-streamer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-lil-sand-eel-streamer/</guid><description>Weekend project. My best friend since childhood recently got into slow pitch jigging in saltwater. He asked if I could make him a sand eel imitating fly to replace the basic mylar teasers on his rig. Was excited to try because whatever fly I’d develop for myself should slay for his purposes.</description></item><item><title>Damsel First Attempt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-damsel-first-attempt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 21:01:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-damsel-first-attempt/</guid><description>So obviously lead eyes are too heavy for a dry fly but this is my first attempt and I&amp;rsquo;m trying to hone technique with the materials I have for salt flies and wooley buggers as I live 2+hours away from fly shops with materials. But here is my first attempt at a Damsel :)</description></item><item><title>Which 5wt: Redington Classic Trout OR Echo Carbon XL?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-which-5wt-redington-classic-trout-or-echo-carbon-xl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-which-5wt-redington-classic-trout-or-echo-carbon-xl/</guid><description>Debating on which one of these I should get for my first 5 wt rod. I&amp;rsquo;m new to fly fishing so when it comes to casting action I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much of a point of reference. I already have a 4 wt and a 6 wt.</description></item><item><title>Diamond Soft Hackles</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-diamond-soft-hackles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:34:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-diamond-soft-hackles/</guid><description>These are some wet n’ dry soft hackles that have produced consistently for me over the years. They’re meant to be fished on a team of three upstream over riffles on warm summer days in the sort of water that dries and weighted nymphs are kind of useless.</description></item><item><title>How to fish my local creek</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-how-to-fish-my-local-creek/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 11:11:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-how-to-fish-my-local-creek/</guid><description>Hey all just posted this on FishingAustralia but I thought I’d get some good advice here as well.I spent 5 hours today fishing this creek with no luck.I used a #2 panther martin (multiple colours), 10lb braid (not ideal | know), and 6lb mono leader.There&amp;rsquo;s pools up to 3 meters deep (murky) and sh&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Josie’s Big Day</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-josie-s-big-day/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-josie-s-big-day/</guid><description>I’ve never had a dog who was a really good fishing partner. When I brought Josie home, I knew that was going be be a goal. My dog and me out on the river, doing our thing without any particular plan. It sounds good on paper but anyone who fishes with dogs knows it isn’t always ideal. Ive definitely had dogs who weren&amp;rsquo;t with the program.</description></item><item><title>❄️Waiting to ride. Here are some of my favorite terrestrials. With Carl’s Cicada’s, a sneaky presentation is key. False cast just behind the fish for aim. Then, cast just ahead of the fish at a 45° angle. Let it drift a bit and then retrieve swiftly but slowly across the fish’s nose. 10/10 🎣</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-waiting-to-ride-here-are-some-of-my-favorite-terrestrials-wi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-waiting-to-ride-here-are-some-of-my-favorite-terrestrials-wi/</guid><description>Read more about ❄️Waiting to ride. Here are some of my favorite terrestrials. With Carl’s Cicada’s, a sneaky presentation is key. False cast just behind the fish for aim. Then, cast just ahead of the fish at a 45° angle. Let it drift a bit and then retrieve swiftly but slowly across the fish’s nose. 10/10 🎣.</description></item><item><title>Fly Fishing 101: How To Choose Your First Fly Rod</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</guid><description>Walk into any fly shop, or browse around online, and you’ll quickly realize there are more fly rod choices out there than questionable food at a casino buffet. In this case, though, picking a less-than-stellar rod won’t give you food poisoning, so there’s a lot less risk involved.</description></item><item><title>Taming Marabou Tails</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move toward spring, the presentation of streamers increases for many fly fishers. For those of us that tie our own, the use of some materials is far more common than others. Marabou tends to be one of those materials, particularly in the tails of many bugger style streamers.</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Fall, What You Should Know About Sinking Fly Lines</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</guid><description>By Garner Reid A GOOD PORTION OF MY FLY FISHING INVOLVES THROWING SOME SORT OF A SINKING FLY LINE. Realistically, half of my time on the water involves streamers and sinking lines at least for some part of the day. If I am not out on the water guiding for streamer-eating fish like stripers, I’m in the fly shop talking about them.</description></item><item><title>How to Tie: The Red Tag Nymph</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:48:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</guid><description>In this week’s “How to Tie” feature, APH Flying Tying shows us a fantastic attractor pattern you can fish all year long, the Red Tag Nymph.</description></item><item><title>Boundary Waters Protection with Matthew Schultz, Fishing Guides’ Favorite Beer Test, and More | TWIFF – Flylords Podcast</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:14:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</guid><description>Follow along as we explore the latest fly fishing news and controversial opinions in This Week in Fly Fishing with Jared and Wills. In this episode, Matthew Schultz with Sportsmen for the Boundary Waters joins the crew to talk about the concerning conservation issues the Boundary Waters are facing.</description></item><item><title>Fly Fishing: Our Trout Rivers and Streams Need More Wood</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-fly-fishing-our-trout-rivers-and-streams-need-more-wood/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-fly-fishing-our-trout-rivers-and-streams-need-more-wood/</guid><description>Several years back, one of my favorite wild trout streams, only a few miles from my house, got slammed with tornados and high winds (from back to back hurricanes that had moved up from Florida). The aftermath from the strong storms, downed dozens, upon dozens of trees along the stream.</description></item><item><title>Fast Pocket Water &amp; Big Attractor Dry Flies</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-fast-pocket-water-big-attractor-dry-flies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-fast-pocket-water-big-attractor-dry-flies/</guid><description>During the spring, summer and fall I often get the itch to forget about catching numbers and instead see how big of an attractor dry fly I can get away with fishing and still fool trout. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, my closest trout waters are North Georgia and Western North Carolina.</description></item><item><title>Trout Spey Unplugged: Mastering Two-Handed Fishing Techniques</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-09-trout-spey-bridging-techniques-for-twohanded-fishi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Feb 2026 08:12:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-09-trout-spey-bridging-techniques-for-twohanded-fishi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you’ve spent any time on the water with a single-handed rod, transitioning to trout Spey can feel like learning to speak a new language while trying to catch a fish. Thankfully, Pete Kutzer’s insights from &amp;lsquo;How to get started in trout Spey&amp;rsquo; break it down into manageable bites. He emphasizes that the essence of two-handed fishing isn’t about showing off your casting skills; it’s about effectively getting your fly in front of the fish. Just like any other technique, it requires practice, but it can be incredibly rewarding, especially when you start swinging streamers in the fall. Speaking of streamers, Bob Reece’s piece on reading aggressive trout body language dovetails nicely into this theme. Knowing how to observe your quarry can help you choose the right approach and leverage that two-handed rod effectively.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Lakes to Lagoons: Your Saltwater Survival Guide</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:06:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fishing might feel like learning to ride a bike again—except this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve got waves, salt, and maybe a shark or two. The insight from fellow anglers shows that while the fundamentals of casting and retrieving remain, the nuances of saltwater fishing require some tweaking. Whether you’re fishing the beaches of La Paz or the jungles of Costa Rica, adapting your skills is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, the Reddit threads where anglers share their saltwater debut experiences. One newbie was thrown right into the chaos of feeding fish, learning that a fast retrieve and the right bait can make all the difference. Or consider the podcast with Kevin Jackson, packing in the reality that not only can you target tarpon and trout on the same trip, but you&amp;rsquo;ll also need to adjust your approach depending on the conditions. So, if you’ve been slinging flies for trout in your local river and think you’re ready for some salt, pay attention. There’s more to it than just casting into the waves and hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Streamers Unleashed: Get Your Big Fish Game On</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-streamers-unleashed-mastering-the-art-of-big-fish-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:05:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-streamers-unleashed-mastering-the-art-of-big-fish-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, folks, let’s talk streamers. Forget what you think you know about delicate dry flies and light tippets—if you want to hook into some serious trout, it&amp;rsquo;s time to embrace the meatier side of life. The latest insights from various corners of the fishing world make it crystal clear: mastering streamer presentation is key to turning sluggish fish into aggressive predators. From understanding how to make your fly dance to reading the body language of those hungry trout, the stakes have never been higher.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tying It All Together: Innovative Techniques to Up Your Fly Game</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-exploring-unique-fly-tying-techniques-from-spey-to/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:07:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-exploring-unique-fly-tying-techniques-from-spey-to/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fly tying isn&amp;rsquo;t just about slapping some feathers onto a hook; it&amp;rsquo;s an art form that combines both tradition and innovation. From the classic Woolly Bugger to the modern marvels like Mallard spey tubes, there&amp;rsquo;s a world of techniques just waiting to enhance your fishing game. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a newbie trying to understand the ropes or a seasoned tyer looking to spice things up, the insights from the latest articles on fly tying offer something for everyone. For instance, take Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s piece on foundational flies — the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis. These are the building blocks that any angler should master before they start diving into the more complex stuff.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Winter Warriors: Mastering the Art of Cold-Water Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-navigating-the-challenges-of-winter-fishing-strate/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:06:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-navigating-the-challenges-of-winter-fishing-strate/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As winter cloaks our beloved waters in a frosty embrace, the art of fishing transforms into a strategic dance of adaptation. Cold water challenges even the most seasoned anglers, requiring a keen understanding of fish behavior and the right tools for success. The articles I&amp;rsquo;ve explored this month shed light on effective tactics for winter fishing, emphasizing the importance of technical approaches and versatile patterns. From the subtlety of midges to the resilience of bright worms, these insights can be your ticket to success amidst the chill.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Tarpon to Techniques: Chasing Saltwater Dreams</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-06-saltwater-adventures-from-tarpon-to-techniques/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 08:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-06-saltwater-adventures-from-tarpon-to-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Saltwater fly fishing is like casting a line into the very essence of adventure itself. As I sift through stories from fellow anglers, it’s clear that every cast brings with it not just the promise of a fish, but a world filled with unforgettable experiences. From the exhilarating strikes of giant Tarpon in the glistening waters off Costa Rica, to the vibrant chaos of sardines frenzied along the beaches of Baja California, each tale reminds me that the ocean&amp;rsquo;s pulse is alive and waiting for us to engage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater to Salt: Navigating the Tides of Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:10:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve trotted from the crystal-clear streams of the Rockies to the azure expanses of the Caribbean, I’ve learned one hard truth: the transition from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing is no mere step; it&amp;rsquo;s a leap across the threshold of two worlds. With each cast, you feel the salt in the air and the pulse of the ocean beneath your feet, and while the tactics may shift, the thrill is a constant. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a freshwater veteran dipping your toes into the salt or a rookie who can’t shake the itch to explore, the skills you’ve honed can be your passport to adventure in the briny deep.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Where Creativity Meets the Water: The Artistic Side of Fly Tying</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-03-the-crossroads-of-art-and-fly-tying-creative-inspi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2026 18:38:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-03-the-crossroads-of-art-and-fly-tying-creative-inspi/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I sit on the banks of the Deschutes, fly rod in hand and the sun dipping low, I can’t help but notice how much fly tying has become an art form in its own right. It’s not just about matching the hatch anymore; it’s about expressing yourself with every feather and thread you wrap around that hook. This theme of blending creativity with technique really shines through in recent articles. Take Duane Hada&amp;rsquo;s tribute mural for the legendary Dave Whitlock, which reminds us that the stories behind our flies are just as important as the flies themselves. His mural isn’t just paint; it’s a homage that pulls the entire community together, anchoring our passion in a shared history.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting Hooked: The Essential Gear and Techniques for Saltwater Fly Fishing Newbies</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Saltwater fly fishing can feel like a rite of passage for many anglers, but for newbies, it’s often a confusing mix of excitement and intimidation. These guys on Reddit are figuring it out in real-time, discussing everything from the right gear to techniques that help bridge the gap between the shore and the fish. If you&amp;rsquo;re diving into the salty depths for the first time, there’s a world of information tucked into their stories—and a few hard-learned lessons to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Master the Stream: Unlocking the Secrets of Streamer Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-streamer-strategies-mastering-presentation-for-tro/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:19:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-streamer-strategies-mastering-presentation-for-tro/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, presentation isn’t just a good idea—it’s the law of the land. If you’re not making that hefty fly shimmy and shake like the last morsel of food in the water, you might as well be casting a brick. I’ve seen the difference a subtle change in technique can make, as highlighted in several articles that dive deep into the nuances of presenting streamers. Whether you’re on a prime tailwater or tackling the fast rapids of Montana, it’s all about how your fly moves through the water. I’ve had my best days when I focus on this aspect, and trust me, it shows in the size of fish you can hook.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Classics: Essential Fly Patterns Every New Tyer Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-the-art-of-tying-classic-patterns-for-new-fly-tyer/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:07:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-the-art-of-tying-classic-patterns-for-new-fly-tyer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest: when it comes to fly tying, the foundation you build is as crucial as the fish you hope to catch. I’ve spent countless hours behind the vise, and trust me, it’s those classic patterns that keep my box stocked and my fishing trips successful. Bob Reece from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline hits the nail on the head by outlining three must-have flies for newbies: the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis. These aren’t just pretty feathers—each of these patterns teaches essential techniques that lay the groundwork for more advanced tying. If you can master these, you’re well on your way to becoming a competent tyer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater Newbie to Saltwater Sage: Navigating the Flats</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:06:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every saltwater angler can recall the moment when they first stepped onto the glistening flats, the sun warming their shoulders and the smell of the ocean mingling with the adrenaline of the chase. Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing can feel like stepping into a different world, and it’s a journey that’s both daunting and exhilarating. Whether you’re a newbie casting for the first time, like the enthusiastic angler who recently shared their experience in La Paz, or you&amp;rsquo;re gearing up with a trusty 9-foot rod and chartreuse fly, the saltwater bug is contagious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Streamers Unleashed: Mastering the Art of Enticing Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-streamers-unleashed-presentation-techniques-for-tr/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:06:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-streamers-unleashed-presentation-techniques-for-tr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Alright, fellow anglers, let&amp;rsquo;s get real about streamers. If you&amp;rsquo;re looking to land those elusive trophy trout, it’s not just about the fly you choose but how you present it. As I’ve learned from countless days on the water (and more broken rods than I care to admit), mastering the presentation can make or break your day. In a recent exploration of streamer tactics, articles from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline and insights from Reddit&amp;rsquo;s fly-tying community really nailed it: the right technique can transform your game from mediocre to mind-blowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saltwater Fly Fishing: From the Flats to the Deep Blue</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that this realm offers a diverse tapestry of adventures, techniques, and gear. From the bustling flats teeming with bonefish and permit to the vast blue waters where mighty tarpon roam, our experiences remind us that every angler can find their niche in the salt. A recent Reddit post highlighted the thrill of a first-time outing in La Paz, where the excitement of live bait and fast retrieves turned a casual day into a memorable adventure. Similarly, tales of epic tarpon days in Costa Rica serve as a testament to the sheer adrenaline and joy these fish can bring to our lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fly Tying Fundamentals: Mastering Seasonal Patterns for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the essentials of fly tying, we recognize that the art is not just about creativity—it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the rhythms of nature and how our patterns can mimic them. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a novice just starting out or an experienced tyer looking to refine your skills, the three classic flies highlighted by Bob Reece—Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis—serve as foundational tools in our fly boxes. These patterns don’t just represent the basics; they embody the versatility and adaptability required across seasons and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Master the Streamer Game: Presentation Techniques for Serious Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-mastering-streamer-strategies-the-art-of-presentat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:06:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-mastering-streamer-strategies-the-art-of-presentat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of streamer fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that our success hinges not just on the fly patterns we choose but primarily on how we present them. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight various techniques and insights that can elevate our fishing game, especially as we transition into the fall months when aggressive trout are on the hunt. From understanding the nuances of our retrieves to adapting our leader lengths and line types, mastering presentation is crucial for enticing those big bites.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Streamers Unleashed: Mastering the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-streamers-unleashed-the-art-of-presentation-for-tr/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 13:26:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-streamers-unleashed-the-art-of-presentation-for-tr/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Streamers have this magical ability to turn an average day on the water into a trophy-hunting adventure. But it&amp;rsquo;s not just about slinging a big piece of fur and feathers into the current; it&amp;rsquo;s all about how you present that offering. As I sifted through some recent articles, a clear theme emerged: mastering the art of streamer presentation can drastically elevate your catch rate, especially when it comes to targeting hefty trout. From snaky sculpins to the infamous Sex Dungeon, the way you manipulate a streamer can be the difference between a tight line and an empty net.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing Silver Dreams: The Allure of Saltwater Fly Fishing Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-exploring-saltwater-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:32:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-exploring-saltwater-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, that unmistakable thrill when the sun-kissed horizon meets the shimmering surface of the ocean. Saltwater fly fishing is not just about the catch; it&amp;rsquo;s an adventure steeped in the salty breeze and the promise of epic battles against nature&amp;rsquo;s finest. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re casting a line in the tropical shallows of La Paz or the wild coasts of Costa Rica, each location offers a unique canvas for your fishing story. Fresh reports from fellow anglers remind us that every cast can lead to both mistakes and triumphs, and it’s in those moments that we discover what it truly means to be a saltwater fly fisherman.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fly Tying 101: Your Essential Guide to Building a Solid Fly Box</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-getting-started-with-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:32:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-getting-started-with-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, you’ve decided to dip your toe into the world of fly tying? Welcome to the club, where every knot has a story and every thread has a purpose. It can feel a bit overwhelming at first, but trust me, the satisfaction of seeing a fish take a fly you’ve painstakingly crafted is unmatched. I’ve scoured the waters of various articles to strip away the fluff and get down to the brass tacks of what you really need to know as you start your fly tying journey.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Winter's Grasp: Mastering Fishing Techniques and Patterns for Cold Water Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-winter-fishing-techniques-and-patterns/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:31:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-winter-fishing-techniques-and-patterns/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As winter casts its icy net over our beloved rivers, the art of fishing demands a shift in strategy. The articles I’ve reviewed highlight a crucial theme: adapting our approach to the lethargic behavior of trout and the ever-changing conditions of our waters. The slow metabolism of trout in these colder months means that our fly patterns need to be more precise and our techniques more refined than ever. Midcurrent&amp;rsquo;s pieces on essential winter midges and technical nymphs provide us with a valuable roadmap into the microcosm of winter fishing.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Streamer: Presentation is Everything</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:30:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to chasing big trout, the name of the game is presentation. A recent deep dive into the world of streamer fishing reveals it&amp;rsquo;s not just about what you throw, but how you throw it. In articles from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline and insights from the r/flytying community, a clear theme emerges: your technique can make or break your day on the water. Whether you’re employing a slow retrieve with a Woolly Bugger or dancing a flashier Sex Dungeon through currents, the nuances of movement are crucial.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Patterns That Hook Fish</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-success/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:11:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we delve into the world of fly tying, it’s clear that mastering a few essential patterns can significantly enhance our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting or looking to refine your skills, understanding the foundational techniques behind classic flies is crucial. Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s article on Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline highlights three timeless patterns—the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis—that not only build our skills but also stand the test of time on the water. Each of these flies offers unique advantages and teaches valuable tying techniques that serve as a springboard for more complex patterns.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Streamers Unleashed: Mastering the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-mastering-streamer-techniques-the-art-of-presentat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:11:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-mastering-streamer-techniques-the-art-of-presentat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, the difference between a good day on the water and a legendary one often boils down to presentation. As we dive into the nuances of this technique, we find that factors like leader length, line choice, and the rhythm of our retrieves can dramatically influence our success. Articles like &amp;lsquo;Fishing Streamers Is Still All About Presentation&amp;rsquo; remind us that whether we’re using a classic Woolly Bugger or an intricate articulated pattern, it’s the dance of the fly in the water that truly entices those aggressive trout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Strategies for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we navigate the diverse seasons of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to adapt our techniques to the ever-changing behaviors of these spirited fish. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall to the subtle nuances of spring creeks, understanding the seasonal dynamics can significantly enhance our angling success. In this roundup, we draw insights from various articles that highlight pivotal strategies for each season, ensuring we&amp;rsquo;re well-equipped to tackle trout no matter the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Basics: Essential Fly Tying Techniques for Beginners</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-tying-techniques-for-beginners/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we embark on our journey into the world of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to establish a solid foundation. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re crafting classic patterns or adapting to seasonal changes, mastering the basics can significantly enhance our success on the water. In this roundup, we explore some of the most accessible flies for beginners and the nuanced techniques that can elevate our tying game. By synthesizing insights from Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; and Midcurrent&amp;rsquo;s Tying Tuesday series, we aim to equip novice tiers with the knowledge to confidently tackle their first creations.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamer Presentation: The Key to Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, the nuances of presentation can make all the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in various discussions—from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline’s insights on the art of streamer movement to Reddit’s lively exchanges about effective patterns—our approach to how we present our flies can be the game-changer. Whether we’re working with articulated patterns or classic sculpin imitations, it’s clear that finesse in our technique is paramount. The water is alive with potential, and it’s our job to entice those fish with the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Techniques for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we journey through the seasons, our approach to trout fishing must evolve alongside the changing conditions. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall trout, as detailed by Bob Reece at Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline, to the vital implications of weather patterns outlined by Fly Lords, we gain a clearer understanding of how to adapt our strategies effectively. We’re reminded that staying attuned to environmental cues not only enhances our success but also deepens our connection to the water we love to fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Vise: Essential Fly Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the art of fly tying, it’s clear that this craft is not only about the patterns we create but also the techniques we employ to bring our creations to life. From the foundational classics highlighted by Bob Reece to the technical nuances needed for winter fishing, there’s a wealth of knowledge available to all levels of tiers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these articles provide valuable insights that can elevate our fly tying game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Strategies for Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of streamer fishing, it becomes evident that success isn’t just a matter of tossing a big fly into the water and hoping for the best. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight a critical theme: the importance of presentation. From the insights shared in Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline about using a long leader and intermediate line to bring your sculpin patterns to life, to the discussion on the deliberate retrieves necessary for patterns like Woolly Buggers, we see that the way our flies behave can make all the difference. Whether we’re fishing in a tailwater or a fast-moving stream, mastering these nuanced techniques can elevate our fishing game substantially.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Essential Patterns Every Angler Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we take a deep dive into the fundamentals of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few foundational patterns can unlock a world of fishing success. From Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s insights in &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers,&amp;rsquo; we learn that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just go-to flies; they are stepping stones to understanding the craft. Each of these flies encapsulates essential techniques that every aspiring tier should grasp, laying the groundwork for more complex creations down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout Techniques: From Seasonal Strategies to Catching Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the world of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that our approach must evolve with the seasons. From the new regulations impacting the White River system to the nuanced techniques required for catching trout during the colder months, we are reminded that adaptability is key to our success on the water. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered showcase not just the challenges we face in maintaining sustainable fish populations, but also the artistry and strategy involved in maximizing our catch rates throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Unleashing the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fly fishing for big trout, mastering the art of streamer presentation is non-negotiable. We’ve gathered insights from seasoned anglers and experts who emphasize that how we present our streamers can make all the difference between a day of empty casts and a net full of trophies. Whether you’re working articulated patterns or classic styles, it’s clear that the magic lies in the dance of the fly through the water. Articles from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline and contributions from the fly-tying community highlight techniques and strategies that can elevate our game, especially as we head into the fall months when trout become more aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Is Original Artwork Allowed? Sci-Fi Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</guid><description>My friends told me to share some of my fly fishing related artwork here. I&amp;rsquo;m a local artist in the Helena, MT area and I create Sci-Fi based artwork that sometimes overlaps with fly fishing. Hope you all enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Fishing Streamers Is Still All About Presentation</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</guid><description>Mastering the art of streamer fishing hinges on presentation—something every fly angler can appreciate, whether you’re tossing a hefty articulated pattern or a classic Maine-style streamer. In a recent outing on a prime Tailwater, I found success working snaky sculpins with a long leader and intermediate line, while my friends experimented with a Sex Dungeon and other variations, proving that it&amp;rsquo;s all about how you make that imitation dance through the water. Tight lines and rising fish await those willing to perfect their technique; dive into the full article for tips on maximizing your streamer game!</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Flats: Saltwater Fly Fishing Techniques and Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the flats present both unique challenges and unforgettable rewards. From the adrenaline rush of landing a giant tarpon in Costa Rica to the strategic nuances of targeting bonefish and permit, our exploration of these articles reveals the depth of skill and knowledge required to truly excel in saltwater environments. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned angler or just wading into the world of saltwater fly fishing, there’s a wealth of insights to glean from the experiences shared by fellow anglers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Fly Tying: Essential Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we immerse ourselves in the essential craft of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few key patterns can lay a solid foundation for our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the vice or looking to refine your skills, articles like Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; remind us that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just staples; they are stepping stones into the broader world of fly tying. These flies offer us the chance to practice crucial techniques, from tying stability to creating lifelike movements in the water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Big Ones: A Saltwater Fly Fishing Odyssey</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the pursuit of species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit offers both challenge and thrill. From firsthand accounts of rookie anglers navigating the beaches of La Paz to the latest gear revelations from Sage, we’re reminded that every cast can lead to a story worth telling. This isn’t just about hooking the big one; it’s about the journey we embark on and the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: Build Your Skills, One Pattern at a Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that the right fly can mean the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. This roundup dives deep into the art of fly tying, an essential skill that not only enhances our angling arsenal but also connects us to the craft in a meaningful way. From novice tiers sharing their first attempts to experienced anglers revisiting the vice after decades, the journey of fly tying is as diverse as the waters we fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Trout Tactics: Mastering the Art and Science of Freshwater Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of trout fishing, we recognize that the pursuit of these elusive fish goes far beyond simply casting a line. From experimenting with unconventional bait, as seen in the Reddit post where a wacky rigged trout worm led to a successful catch, to understanding the body language of aggressive trout in fall, our journey is filled with insights that can elevate our angling game. We’re not just fishing; we’re learning to communicate with the fish in their own language—be it through the right flies or the perfect presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nice stocked Rainbow</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</guid><description>Was throwing lures all morning with no follows or hits. Tried something a bit unconventional and was able to hook into this one with two trout worms wacky rigged on a trout magnet jig under a bobber. Close to 15 inches.</description></item><item><title>First fly since 1993, and it's ugly.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</guid><description>Got bored and had access to a while bunch of fly tying supplies. Figured I should likely have a concept of it being the local fly club president. haven&amp;rsquo;t tied a fly since 1993 at the Scout jamboree. seems to have turned out fine, not sure if it would survive a cast. Not sure what it&amp;rsquo;s for.</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Fishing Sunglasses (Sanofan Fluid Tint)</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</guid><description>I’ve replied to a couple of posts in this sub with my recommendation for the best fly fishing sunglasses I’ve ever used, so I figure I’d make a post about these. These Sanofan Fluid Tints are not only the best value for money fishing sunnies I’ve ever seen, but just downright the best I’ve ever used (mauis, smiths, etc).</description></item><item><title>Reading The Body Language of Highly Aggressive Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move into the fall months, the use of streamer patterns typically increases for many fly fishers. There are many factors that lead to success when pursuing trout with these beefy creations. Evaluating the body language of the aggressive fish that chase these flies can improve your odds of hooking up.</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>What Current Fly Rods Will Be Collectibles In 20 Years?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</guid><description>Some fly rods end up as more than just another entry in that year’s product catalog. A select few gain a cult following, often retaining their value (and exceeding their original retail price) as the years march on.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Patterns Worth Your Vise Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</link><pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 11:18:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-13-tying-tuesday-patterns-worth-your-vise-time/</guid><description>From micro-midges to bright worms, the range here reflects the reality of cold-water fishing: you need options.</description></item><item><title>How to get started in trout Spey with Pete Kutzer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</guid><description>Any kind of two-handed fishing is confusing for those of us who mostly fish with a single-handed rod. I asked the great Pete Kutzer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: 14 Tips for Spring Creek Fishing, with Brant Oswald</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</guid><description>Brant Oswald [23:20] is a veteran guide, teacher, and fly shop operator with over 40 years in the business&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>So you want a job in the fly-fishing industry? With Kirk Deeter</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</guid><description>I get regular questions from people about getting a job in the fly-fishing industry, both in the podcast mailbox and in person at shows and store visits. It&amp;rsquo;s a tough question and I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers so I called upon my buddy Kirk Deeter&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>North American and European fly-tying cross pollination with Barry Ord Clarke</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 05:32:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</guid><description>Barry Ord Clarke is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular fly tiers, through his books, videos, and web site. Originally from the UK but living in Norway, Barry keeps&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>