<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Gear on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/gear/</link><description>Recent content in Gear on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:11:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/gear/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Don Gapen Style Muddlers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-don-gapen-style-muddlers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 22:11:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-don-gapen-style-muddlers/</guid><description>Bozeman rod maker Bill Blackurn made these Doh Gapen style MuddlersIt might have been Dah Bailey who popularized the clipped head incrrnation. Dan was a gift to civilization. But I do still like the original Muddlers best.</description></item><item><title>Men and Their Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-men-and-their-adventures/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-men-and-their-adventures/</guid><description>“Cuba is two weeks from today!!! Got to admit I’m a little nervous going where my phone and credit cards don’t work, and taking some ancient helicopter.” That’s the text I got from my buddy Geoff this morning. He’s had this Cuba trip planned for almost a year but it’s only now sinking in.</description></item><item><title>Ocean fly fishing - gear recommendations</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-ocean-fly-fishing-gear-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-ocean-fly-fishing-gear-recommendations/</guid><description>I want to go to baja to fly fish for marlin, tunas, dorados, roosterfish, etc.Where do you buy gear for thiskind of fishing? Cabela’s and bass pro rarely has any wt 11/12 rods. What is the right setup for rod, line, etc for this?</description></item><item><title>Gear Help</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-gear-help/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 03:39:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-gear-help/</guid><description>I’m getting into the sport a bit more now and I’m looking at getting a 9’ 5wt redington classic trout while I have some spare change but I was wondering how important the reel really is? I’m looking to stay around the $300-$350 total between rod and reel.If anyone has other recommendations please&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Winston Air 2 Fly Rod: A Long Haul Review</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-winston-air-2-fly-rod-a-long-haul-review/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-winston-air-2-fly-rod-a-long-haul-review/</guid><description>The Long Haul review series is crafted to give you an honest, in-depth look at how products perform over time.</description></item><item><title>How to Optimize Your Drift Boat Storage</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-how-to-optimize-your-drift-boat-storage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 15:00:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-how-to-optimize-your-drift-boat-storage/</guid><description>Fly fishing boats are tight spaces by design. Between rods, fly line, nets, and all the random essentials that pile up over the course of a day, it doesn’t take much for a clean setup to turn into a mess.</description></item><item><title>Anyone else swear by Panther Martins for stream trout?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-anyone-else-swear-by-panther-martins-for-stream-trout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 11:36:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-anyone-else-swear-by-panther-martins-for-stream-trout/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been slaying trout in the small streams near Nederland using Panther Martin spinners. I like the black body with the yellow spots. Anyone else have a go-to lure for high-mountain streams around here? Always looking to expand my tackle box, lol.</description></item><item><title>My Experience At The G&amp;G Bonefish School</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-my-experience-at-the-g-g-bonefish-school/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 08:58:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-my-experience-at-the-g-g-bonefish-school/</guid><description>By Jason Tucker I could not have been more shocked to find myself in the Bahamas than if my spaceship had crashed there. The call came on Thursday. “Can you go to the Bahamas for a week?” “When?” “We leave Saturday.” I checked with my employer, girlfriend and bank account. For once in my life the answer was yes.</description></item><item><title>1st Brown of the '26</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-1st-brown-of-the-26/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 06:33:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-1st-brown-of-the-26/</guid><description>Had no luck pulling streamers, switched to the BFS rod and caught 3 over 22in in the last half hour. Slowly twitching a brown Yum hellgrammite on ned rig across the sandy bottom by the weed beds.</description></item><item><title>Had a pretty spectacular day. Went 2 for 6 on steelhead and a couple browns to hand. The "GoTo" continues to produce.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-had-a-pretty-spectacular-day-went-2-for-6-on-steelhead-and-a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 22:29:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-had-a-pretty-spectacular-day-went-2-for-6-on-steelhead-and-a/</guid><description>Read more about Had a pretty spectacular day. Went 2 for 6 on steelhead and a couple browns to hand. The &amp;ldquo;GoTo&amp;rdquo; continues to produce..</description></item><item><title>2026 F3T Behind the Lens: Black Sheep</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-black-sheep/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 21:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-black-sheep/</guid><description>Jako Lucas is no stranger to the Fly Fishing Film Tour, nor far-off, stoke-filled destination fishing adventures. For this installment of F3T Behind the Lens, we sat down with the team behind Black Sheep: Jako Lucas of CaptainJack Productions and Wade Kelly of Flow State Productions.</description></item><item><title>So You Wanna Run Down the Man?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-so-you-wanna-run-down-the-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-so-you-wanna-run-down-the-man/</guid><description>Roosterfish(pez gallo) in my opinion, are by far one the hardest fighting and elusive fish that can be pursued with a fly rod.</description></item><item><title>Nymphing off the mothership</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-nymphing-off-the-mothership/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-nymphing-off-the-mothership/</guid><description>I was looking through old pictures from when I was guiding from a mothership in Oman. We would get schools of fish hanging out in our lights at night, and I figured out I could drift little flies to them in the tidal current.Pictured are a Lunar Fusilier, a black tip trevally, a striped fusilier, a flagtail, a wave Garrick/dart.</description></item><item><title>Seeking a Tarpon Guide - Destin FL</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</guid><description>I’ll be in the Destin, FL area this June and would love the chance to target tarpon on the fly. So far, I’ve only found one charter that specifically offers tarpon fly fishing trips.</description></item><item><title>High alpine season can’t come soon enough</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-high-alpine-season-can-t-come-soon-enough/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 15:42:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-high-alpine-season-can-t-come-soon-enough/</guid><description>Finally getting around to sorting photos from this past season. One of the fattest trout I’ve ever seen, and no slouch in the length department either</description></item><item><title>Fly Fisherman - April/May 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-fly-fisherman-april-may-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:42:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-fly-fisherman-april-may-2026/</guid><description>Fly Fisherman is the world&amp;rsquo;s leading magazine for fly fishing. Every issue provides expert advice on the latest fly fishing techniques, the newest tackle and the hottest new fly patterns. Through informative articles, it highlights the best destinations for t…</description></item><item><title>Glass or Graphite, What’s Right For You?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-glass-or-graphite-what-s-right-for-you/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-glass-or-graphite-what-s-right-for-you/</guid><description>When choosing between graphite and fiberglass fly rods, it’s smart to consider where and how you fish. I got an email the other day from a reader. Here’s an excerpt: “I am looking at a 7wt predominantly for trout and smallmouth here in Tennessee.</description></item><item><title>Budget Skagit line system?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-budget-skagit-line-system/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 03:14:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-budget-skagit-line-system/</guid><description>I was given a Spey rod/reel setup by a relative a while back, but the line on it is not actually designed for Spey.</description></item><item><title>8 or 9wt as a second rod? Would you recommend the Fenwick HMG?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-8-or-9wt-as-a-second-rod-would-you-recommend-the-fenwick-hmg/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:34:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-8-or-9wt-as-a-second-rod-would-you-recommend-the-fenwick-hmg/</guid><description>Hi everyone,I’m actively shopping for a second fly fishing rod in anticipation of next season. I currently have a 5wt setup that I bought last year to target trout and smallies.I’m looking for a second setup to complement it and I’m wondering if I should go with a 8wt or 9wt.</description></item><item><title>The Drift: Are Fly Rod Warranties Worth It?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-the-drift-are-fly-rod-warranties-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-the-drift-are-fly-rod-warranties-worth-it/</guid><description>While working in a fly shop once, an angler came in with a broken rod that he needed help sending in for warranty work. The manufacturer of the rod offered complete replacements, but did request that the angler explain how the rod was broken.</description></item><item><title>Help greatly appreciated</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-help-greatly-appreciated/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 13:25:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-help-greatly-appreciated/</guid><description>Hi all, I’m an 19M and have fished for the best part of 10 years, however only ever done float, spinning and sea fishing. Recently i have inherited some fly fishing equipment which i am desperate to get out and try. However im finding the range of flys and types of line quite overwhelming and leaving me clueless what to use.</description></item><item><title>Build Your Own Fly Rod: DIY Video 7</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-build-your-own-fly-rod-diy-video-7/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 08:58:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-build-your-own-fly-rod-diy-video-7/</guid><description>THAT NEW DIY FLY ROD IS JUST ABOUT READY TO FISH. In this, the last video of the series, Matt Draft, of Proof Fly Fishing, shows you how to fix some common problems that happen when building a rod. These helpful techniques will ensure that your rod is perfect and will help with future repairs. I hope you have enjoyed this series.</description></item><item><title>Traveling with Waders/Boots</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-traveling-with-waders-boots/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 02:59:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-traveling-with-waders-boots/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve never flown for a fly fishing trip, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be flying out to PA this spring and plan on getting some fishing in. How are people traveling with waders/boots? I see tons of options for transporting rods/reels, but less specific options for traveling with waders and boots.</description></item><item><title>Newbie needs advice</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-newbie-needs-advice/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 01:45:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-newbie-needs-advice/</guid><description>Me and a buddy who are relatively new to the fly fishing world are planning a trip to the snake and Missouri rivers around late June and need some advice.</description></item><item><title>Antique market find</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-antique-market-find/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 17:09:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-antique-market-find/</guid><description>bought an old tackle box for 20$ at an antique market last October.</description></item><item><title>Thoughts on a Winston Air 2 864</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-thoughts-on-a-winston-air-2-864/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 03:45:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-thoughts-on-a-winston-air-2-864/</guid><description>I want to get a higher end rod, starting with a range I generally fish a lot. A light all around fly rod, sans euro styles. This range suffices a majority of my fishing.it seems Winston stepped out a bit from their dry fly only vibe and the Air 2 looks appealing but I have not spoke with anyone who has fished one.</description></item><item><title>First proper fish</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-first-proper-fish/</link><pubDate>Sun, 22 Feb 2026 00:02:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-22-first-proper-fish/</guid><description>Caught a few smolt this winter but this is my first proper sized fish on a fly rod and my first steelhead/lake-run rainbow. Egg pattern under an indicator on a 6wt.</description></item><item><title>Fly line recommendations</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-fly-line-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 22:22:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-fly-line-recommendations/</guid><description>So
I recently purchased a 7 foot 63 weight that I plan to use in small streams and little ponds for bluegill and trout. What&amp;rsquo;s some good lines you guys use on a 3 weight rod, I&amp;rsquo;m assuming just a standard wait forward floating line? Bit open to different ideas. I currently own a 8 weight and a 6 and a 5 weight.This is my first 3 weight.</description></item><item><title>Which 5wt: Redington Classic Trout OR Echo Carbon XL?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-which-5wt-redington-classic-trout-or-echo-carbon-xl/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:51:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-which-5wt-redington-classic-trout-or-echo-carbon-xl/</guid><description>Debating on which one of these I should get for my first 5 wt rod. I&amp;rsquo;m new to fly fishing so when it comes to casting action I don&amp;rsquo;t really have much of a point of reference. I already have a 4 wt and a 6 wt.</description></item><item><title>Diamond Soft Hackles</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-diamond-soft-hackles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 19:34:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-diamond-soft-hackles/</guid><description>These are some wet n’ dry soft hackles that have produced consistently for me over the years. They’re meant to be fished on a team of three upstream over riffles on warm summer days in the sort of water that dries and weighted nymphs are kind of useless.</description></item><item><title>Josie’s Big Day</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-josie-s-big-day/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-josie-s-big-day/</guid><description>I’ve never had a dog who was a really good fishing partner. When I brought Josie home, I knew that was going be be a goal. My dog and me out on the river, doing our thing without any particular plan. It sounds good on paper but anyone who fishes with dogs knows it isn’t always ideal. Ive definitely had dogs who weren&amp;rsquo;t with the program.</description></item><item><title>Euro nymphing rod for dry flies?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-euro-nymphing-rod-for-dry-flies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-euro-nymphing-rod-for-dry-flies/</guid><description>I recently ordered a diamondback gen 4 online. The more I’m researching, it almost seems as though it could be viable as a dry fly rod as well. Is this true? If so, what qualities that a euro rod have that cross over into a dry fly rod? I purchase a 10’7”3wt. I know that there’s no “rules” but I want some opinions and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Fly Fishing 101: How To Choose Your First Fly Rod</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</guid><description>Walk into any fly shop, or browse around online, and you’ll quickly realize there are more fly rod choices out there than questionable food at a casino buffet. In this case, though, picking a less-than-stellar rod won’t give you food poisoning, so there’s a lot less risk involved.</description></item><item><title>Finner Excel Fly Outfit</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-finner-excel-fly-outfit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 13:35:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-finner-excel-fly-outfit/</guid><description>&lt;a href="https://www.finner.co.uk/products/xcel-fly-fishing-rodAnyone"&gt;https://www.finner.co.uk/products/xcel-fly-fishing-rodAnyone&lt;/a&gt; have experience with or opinions on the above? I’m looking at upgrading from my Temu Sougayilang special.TIA!</description></item><item><title>Taming Marabou Tails</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move toward spring, the presentation of streamers increases for many fly fishers. For those of us that tie our own, the use of some materials is far more common than others. Marabou tends to be one of those materials, particularly in the tails of many bugger style streamers.</description></item><item><title>Need some help</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-need-some-help/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:23:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-need-some-help/</guid><description>I don’t really know what I’m doing yet. I’m going backpacking with friends and we’re planning to try and catch trout. I’m thinking about getting the Daiwa Megaforce Travel Rod 2.10 m because it folds down small enough to fit in my backpack.I’d like to invest in decent gear without breaking the bank, but I’m confused about line sizes.</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Fall, What You Should Know About Sinking Fly Lines</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</guid><description>By Garner Reid A GOOD PORTION OF MY FLY FISHING INVOLVES THROWING SOME SORT OF A SINKING FLY LINE. Realistically, half of my time on the water involves streamers and sinking lines at least for some part of the day. If I am not out on the water guiding for streamer-eating fish like stripers, I’m in the fly shop talking about them.</description></item><item><title>How to Tie: The Red Tag Nymph</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:48:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</guid><description>In this week’s “How to Tie” feature, APH Flying Tying shows us a fantastic attractor pattern you can fish all year long, the Red Tag Nymph.</description></item><item><title>Boundary Waters Protection with Matthew Schultz, Fishing Guides’ Favorite Beer Test, and More | TWIFF – Flylords Podcast</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:14:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</guid><description>Follow along as we explore the latest fly fishing news and controversial opinions in This Week in Fly Fishing with Jared and Wills. In this episode, Matthew Schultz with Sportsmen for the Boundary Waters joins the crew to talk about the concerning conservation issues the Boundary Waters are facing.</description></item><item><title>DENVER FLY FISHING SHOW: NEW PRODUCTS OF 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-denver-fly-fishing-show-new-products-of-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-denver-fly-fishing-show-new-products-of-2026/</guid><description>Each winter, brands bring new and updated gear to the Denver Fly Fishing Show. It’s a chance to see what’s changing, what’s being refined, and what products are making their way into anglers’ hands in the coming season.</description></item><item><title>Last Cast Bonefish</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-last-cast-bonefish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-last-cast-bonefish/</guid><description>Bonefishing, for me, is the purest form of the drug. I’m just returning from the first of three G&amp;amp;G Bonefish Schools in the Bahamas. This trip was more of a reunion than a school, with better than half of the anglers returning for the second or third time.</description></item><item><title>Olympic Peninsula Steelhead Won’t Get ESA Protection—Despite “Moderate Risk of Extinction”</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-olympic-peninsula-steelhead-won-t-get-esa-protection-despite/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 13:21:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-olympic-peninsula-steelhead-won-t-get-esa-protection-despite/</guid><description>NOAA&amp;rsquo;s decision not to list OP steelhead under the ESA has conservation groups reviewing legal options and demanding immediate action from state and tribal co-managers — all while the peak of the wild winter run is underway. Image by Hone Creative</description></item><item><title>From Lakes to Lagoons: Your Saltwater Survival Guide</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:06:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fishing might feel like learning to ride a bike again—except this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve got waves, salt, and maybe a shark or two. The insight from fellow anglers shows that while the fundamentals of casting and retrieving remain, the nuances of saltwater fishing require some tweaking. Whether you’re fishing the beaches of La Paz or the jungles of Costa Rica, adapting your skills is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, the Reddit threads where anglers share their saltwater debut experiences. One newbie was thrown right into the chaos of feeding fish, learning that a fast retrieve and the right bait can make all the difference. Or consider the podcast with Kevin Jackson, packing in the reality that not only can you target tarpon and trout on the same trip, but you&amp;rsquo;ll also need to adjust your approach depending on the conditions. So, if you’ve been slinging flies for trout in your local river and think you’re ready for some salt, pay attention. There’s more to it than just casting into the waves and hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting Hooked: The Essential Gear and Techniques for Saltwater Fly Fishing Newbies</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Saltwater fly fishing can feel like a rite of passage for many anglers, but for newbies, it’s often a confusing mix of excitement and intimidation. These guys on Reddit are figuring it out in real-time, discussing everything from the right gear to techniques that help bridge the gap between the shore and the fish. If you&amp;rsquo;re diving into the salty depths for the first time, there’s a world of information tucked into their stories—and a few hard-learned lessons to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater Newbie to Saltwater Sage: Navigating the Flats</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:06:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every saltwater angler can recall the moment when they first stepped onto the glistening flats, the sun warming their shoulders and the smell of the ocean mingling with the adrenaline of the chase. Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing can feel like stepping into a different world, and it’s a journey that’s both daunting and exhilarating. Whether you’re a newbie casting for the first time, like the enthusiastic angler who recently shared their experience in La Paz, or you&amp;rsquo;re gearing up with a trusty 9-foot rod and chartreuse fly, the saltwater bug is contagious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Essential Fly Fishing Gear: The Must-Haves for Every Angler's Arsenal</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-fly-fishing-gear-essentials-what-you-need/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-fly-fishing-gear-essentials-what-you-need/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the world of fly fishing gear, it’s clear that having the right equipment can make all the difference on the water. From the latest innovations in rods like the Orvis Recon to specialized reels like Sage&amp;rsquo;s Enforcer Grand Slam, our gear choices play a pivotal role in our fishing success. Each piece of gear not only enhances our experience but also reflects our personal style and fishing goals. Whether we’re targeting freshwater trout or saltwater species, understanding the essentials ensures we&amp;rsquo;re prepared for whatever the day brings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gear Up: Must-Have Equipment for the Modern Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-essential-equipment-for-every-angler/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-essential-equipment-for-every-angler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for another season of fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to assess the tools at our disposal. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re seasoned veterans or newcomers to the sport, understanding the latest in fly fishing equipment can significantly enhance our experience on the water. From rods that offer unparalleled performance to gifts that every angler will appreciate, we’ve gathered insights from recent articles that highlight what we should consider for our next fishing adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One of my biggest accomplishments yet</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</guid><description>One of my biggest accomplishments so far, the California heritage trout challenge. Fort the first trout, I went up to the Tahoe area to catch the Lahontan cutthrot trout.</description></item><item><title>Gear Up: Elevate Your Fly Fishing Game with the Latest Must-Haves</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-the-best-fly-fishing-equipment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:49:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-the-best-fly-fishing-equipment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for another season on the water, it’s crucial to stay informed about the latest advancements in fly fishing equipment. Recent discussions surrounding the new Orvis Recon rod have sparked a lively debate in our community. With its impressive blend of performance and affordability, it’s no wonder anglers are eager to see if this rod lives up to the hype. However, we should also reflect on the broader question: do we sometimes place too much importance on the gear itself? The Drift article reminds us that while top-tier rods can enhance our experience, the joy of fly fishing ultimately comes from our connection to the water and the fish we pursue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Essential Gear Guide: Equip Yourself for Fly Fishing Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-gear-up-the-essentials-for-every-angler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:06:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-gear-up-the-essentials-for-every-angler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for our next fishing adventure, it’s crucial to ensure we have the right tools at our disposal. From protective eyewear to reliable rods, our gear can make or break the experience on the water. In this roundup, we delve into the must-haves every fly angler should consider, drawing insights from fellow anglers who have shared their favorite essentials. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a novice casting your first line or a seasoned pro refining your setup, there’s something here for everyone looking to elevate their fishing game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Big Ones: A Saltwater Fly Fishing Odyssey</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the pursuit of species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit offers both challenge and thrill. From firsthand accounts of rookie anglers navigating the beaches of La Paz to the latest gear revelations from Sage, we’re reminded that every cast can lead to a story worth telling. This isn’t just about hooking the big one; it’s about the journey we embark on and the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Nice stocked Rainbow</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</guid><description>Was throwing lures all morning with no follows or hits. Tried something a bit unconventional and was able to hook into this one with two trout worms wacky rigged on a trout magnet jig under a bobber. Close to 15 inches.</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>Saltwater bug</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:49:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</guid><description>Got my birthday present a little early. Headed out to the beach today. Make no mistake, I am as newbie as they come but I just couldn’t stay out of the water. 9ft rod, 9line, rio saltwater leader…just used the chartreuse fly today. Looked like a fool for the first 30 mins, but got to feeling it after that. Had one hit and miss but that feeling.</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>Is the New Orvis Recon the Best Rod for the Money? Our Thoughts</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</guid><description>Orvis just announced the newest addition to its fly rod lineup, the redesigned Recon series. Since the release of the first Recon back in 2015, this rod has developed a huge following as a mid-priced, performance-driven fly rod.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>The Drift: Do We Care Too Much About Fly Rods?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-the-drift-do-we-care-too-much-about-fly-rods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:43:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-the-drift-do-we-care-too-much-about-fly-rods/</guid><description>Last week, I wrote about my close encounter with a highly-collectible rod, the Winston 8’6″ 4-weight BIIt, nicknamed “The Staff of Moses.” I’m still kicking myself for not buying it (despite the $800+ price tag), but hopefully when the next one comes along, I’ll have some extra cash laying around.</description></item><item><title>Sage Unveils Limited Edition Enforcer Grand Slam Reels: A Collector’s Dream for Flats Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</guid><description>The three-model collection pays tribute to the legendary saltwater &amp;ldquo;Grand Slam&amp;rdquo;—the rare feat of landing a bonefish, permit, and tarpon in a single day.</description></item><item><title>What Current Fly Rods Will Be Collectibles In 20 Years?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</guid><description>Some fly rods end up as more than just another entry in that year’s product catalog. A select few gain a cult following, often retaining their value (and exceeding their original retail price) as the years march on.</description></item><item><title>How to get started in trout Spey with Pete Kutzer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</guid><description>Any kind of two-handed fishing is confusing for those of us who mostly fish with a single-handed rod. I asked the great Pete Kutzer&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>