<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorials on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/tutorials/</link><description>Recent content in Tutorials on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/tutorials/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mastering the Vise: Essential Fly Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-the-art-of-fly-tying-patterns-and-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the art of fly tying, it’s clear that this craft is not only about the patterns we create but also the techniques we employ to bring our creations to life. From the foundational classics highlighted by Bob Reece to the technical nuances needed for winter fishing, there’s a wealth of knowledge available to all levels of tiers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re just starting out or looking to refine your skills, these articles provide valuable insights that can elevate our fly tying game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: Build Your Skills, One Pattern at a Time</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that the right fly can mean the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. This roundup dives deep into the art of fly tying, an essential skill that not only enhances our angling arsenal but also connects us to the craft in a meaningful way. From novice tiers sharing their first attempts to experienced anglers revisiting the vice after decades, the journey of fly tying is as diverse as the waters we fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>