<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saltwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/saltwater/</link><description>Recent content in Saltwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:08:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/saltwater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Saltwater Fly Fishing: From the Flats to the Deep Blue</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that this realm offers a diverse tapestry of adventures, techniques, and gear. From the bustling flats teeming with bonefish and permit to the vast blue waters where mighty tarpon roam, our experiences remind us that every angler can find their niche in the salt. A recent Reddit post highlighted the thrill of a first-time outing in La Paz, where the excitement of live bait and fast retrieves turned a casual day into a memorable adventure. Similarly, tales of epic tarpon days in Costa Rica serve as a testament to the sheer adrenaline and joy these fish can bring to our lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Grand Slam: Mastering the Saltwater Flats Experience</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel the thrill that comes with targeting species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit—collectively known as the Grand Slam. Our exploration of this unique fishing environment, from the stunning flats of La Paz to Costa Rica&amp;rsquo;s rich waters, showcases techniques that not only enhance our skills but also deepen our appreciation for the sport. Anglers everywhere are discovering that the saltwater experience is about much more than just the catch; it&amp;rsquo;s about embracing the vibrant ecosystems and the sheer unpredictability of the ocean&amp;rsquo;s offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing Silver Kings: Our Guide to Tarpon Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of tarpon fishing, we find ourselves captivated by the incredible stories and insights shared by fellow anglers. From the thrill of battling the &amp;lsquo;silver king&amp;rsquo; in Costa Rica to the humbling experience of learning on the beach with a simple fly rod, the journey of targeting tarpon is one filled with highs and lows that unite us all as fishermen. In one Reddit post, a seasoned angler shares the joys of what they call a &amp;lsquo;giant tarpon day,&amp;rsquo; while another recounts their rookie experience that sparked an unquenchable thirst for saltwater fishing. These narratives remind us that every great angler starts somewhere, and it&amp;rsquo;s the pursuit of these majestic fish that binds our community together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Waters and Fisheries</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we are not just participants in a sport; we are stewards of our waters. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight pressing conservation issues across various regions, reminding us that our fishing experiences are deeply intertwined with the health of aquatic ecosystems. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at revitalizing trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that the fight for our fisheries is both complex and critical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Flats: Saltwater Fly Fishing Techniques and Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the flats present both unique challenges and unforgettable rewards. From the adrenaline rush of landing a giant tarpon in Costa Rica to the strategic nuances of targeting bonefish and permit, our exploration of these articles reveals the depth of skill and knowledge required to truly excel in saltwater environments. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned angler or just wading into the world of saltwater fly fishing, there’s a wealth of insights to glean from the experiences shared by fellow anglers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Big Ones: A Saltwater Fly Fishing Odyssey</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the pursuit of species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit offers both challenge and thrill. From firsthand accounts of rookie anglers navigating the beaches of La Paz to the latest gear revelations from Sage, we’re reminded that every cast can lead to a story worth telling. This isn’t just about hooking the big one; it’s about the journey we embark on and the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>There are good days... and then there are giant Tarpon days 😎🇨🇷🇨🇷</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 09:27:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qlrewl"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flyfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saltwater bug</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:49:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</guid><description>Got my birthday present a little early. Headed out to the beach today. Make no mistake, I am as newbie as they come but I just couldn’t stay out of the water. 9ft rod, 9line, rio saltwater leader…just used the chartreuse fly today. Looked like a fool for the first 30 mins, but got to feeling it after that. Had one hit and miss but that feeling.</description></item><item><title>Sage Unveils Limited Edition Enforcer Grand Slam Reels: A Collector’s Dream for Flats Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</guid><description>The three-model collection pays tribute to the legendary saltwater &amp;ldquo;Grand Slam&amp;rdquo;—the rare feat of landing a bonefish, permit, and tarpon in a single day.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Trout, Tarpon, and Other Critters in Costa Rica, with Kevin Jackson</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</guid><description>Did you know you can catch trout and tarpon in the same trip, along with exotic jungle species? I didn&amp;rsquo;t either, but Kevin Jackson [42:22] of Fly Fish Costa Rica shares&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>