<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Saltwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/saltwater/</link><description>Recent content in Saltwater on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:45:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/saltwater/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ocean fly fishing - gear recommendations</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-ocean-fly-fishing-gear-recommendations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Feb 2026 04:45:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-27-ocean-fly-fishing-gear-recommendations/</guid><description>I want to go to baja to fly fish for marlin, tunas, dorados, roosterfish, etc.Where do you buy gear for thiskind of fishing? Cabela’s and bass pro rarely has any wt 11/12 rods. What is the right setup for rod, line, etc for this?</description></item><item><title>My Experience At The G&amp;G Bonefish School</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-my-experience-at-the-g-g-bonefish-school/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 08:58:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-26-my-experience-at-the-g-g-bonefish-school/</guid><description>By Jason Tucker I could not have been more shocked to find myself in the Bahamas than if my spaceship had crashed there. The call came on Thursday. “Can you go to the Bahamas for a week?” “When?” “We leave Saturday.” I checked with my employer, girlfriend and bank account. For once in my life the answer was yes.</description></item><item><title>So You Wanna Run Down the Man?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-so-you-wanna-run-down-the-man/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-so-you-wanna-run-down-the-man/</guid><description>Roosterfish(pez gallo) in my opinion, are by far one the hardest fighting and elusive fish that can be pursued with a fly rod.</description></item><item><title>Nymphing off the mothership</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-nymphing-off-the-mothership/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 07:09:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-25-nymphing-off-the-mothership/</guid><description>I was looking through old pictures from when I was guiding from a mothership in Oman. We would get schools of fish hanging out in our lights at night, and I figured out I could drift little flies to them in the tidal current.Pictured are a Lunar Fusilier, a black tip trevally, a striped fusilier, a flagtail, a wave Garrick/dart.</description></item><item><title>Seeking a Tarpon Guide - Destin FL</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 23:32:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-seeking-a-tarpon-guide-destin-fl/</guid><description>I’ll be in the Destin, FL area this June and would love the chance to target tarpon on the fly. So far, I’ve only found one charter that specifically offers tarpon fly fishing trips.</description></item><item><title>Best value saltwater fishing for ≈5k?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-best-value-saltwater-fishing-for-5k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 02:30:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-24-best-value-saltwater-fishing-for-5k/</guid><description>Planning a trip this spring/summer and trying to figure out the best bang for my buck.</description></item><item><title>When the trout don’t hit the snook do.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-when-the-trout-don-t-hit-the-snook-do/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Feb 2026 22:35:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-23-when-the-trout-don-t-hit-the-snook-do/</guid><description>We live in WNC and typically can’t fish to much this time of year. But the fishing down in Florida when we went down there for the holidays was great! Caught this one on a really small ep bait fish pattern. Looked like an Everglades special.</description></item><item><title>Lil sand eel streamer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-lil-sand-eel-streamer/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 22:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-lil-sand-eel-streamer/</guid><description>Weekend project. My best friend since childhood recently got into slow pitch jigging in saltwater. He asked if I could make him a sand eel imitating fly to replace the basic mylar teasers on his rig. Was excited to try because whatever fly I’d develop for myself should slay for his purposes.</description></item><item><title>BTT and Derek DeYoung License Plate Collaboration Supports Saltwater Conservation</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-btt-and-derek-deyoung-license-plate-collaboration-supports-s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 18:00:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-btt-and-derek-deyoung-license-plate-collaboration-supports-s/</guid><description>Bonefish &amp;amp; Tarpon Trust (BTT) is leading the charge in terms of warm water flats fishing conservation. Since its inception, BTT has been at the forefront of conservation, new research, and habitat restoration, all to benefit tarpon, bonefish, and permit.</description></item><item><title>Florida Sportsman - March 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-florida-sportsman-march-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-florida-sportsman-march-2026/</guid><description>Florida Sportsman is known well for featuring articles on all types of fishing, ranging from fly fishing and other types of inshore angling to fishing done in deeper ocean waters. These articles inform the magazines readers on what types of fish are in season…</description></item><item><title>From Lakes to Lagoons: Your Saltwater Survival Guide</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Feb 2026 08:06:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-08-the-saltwater-transition-tips-for-freshwater-angle/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fishing might feel like learning to ride a bike again—except this time, you&amp;rsquo;ve got waves, salt, and maybe a shark or two. The insight from fellow anglers shows that while the fundamentals of casting and retrieving remain, the nuances of saltwater fishing require some tweaking. Whether you’re fishing the beaches of La Paz or the jungles of Costa Rica, adapting your skills is crucial.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Take, for example, the Reddit threads where anglers share their saltwater debut experiences. One newbie was thrown right into the chaos of feeding fish, learning that a fast retrieve and the right bait can make all the difference. Or consider the podcast with Kevin Jackson, packing in the reality that not only can you target tarpon and trout on the same trip, but you&amp;rsquo;ll also need to adjust your approach depending on the conditions. So, if you’ve been slinging flies for trout in your local river and think you’re ready for some salt, pay attention. There’s more to it than just casting into the waves and hoping for the best.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Tarpon to Techniques: Chasing Saltwater Dreams</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-06-saltwater-adventures-from-tarpon-to-techniques/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Feb 2026 08:10:45 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-06-saltwater-adventures-from-tarpon-to-techniques/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Saltwater fly fishing is like casting a line into the very essence of adventure itself. As I sift through stories from fellow anglers, it’s clear that every cast brings with it not just the promise of a fish, but a world filled with unforgettable experiences. From the exhilarating strikes of giant Tarpon in the glistening waters off Costa Rica, to the vibrant chaos of sardines frenzied along the beaches of Baja California, each tale reminds me that the ocean&amp;rsquo;s pulse is alive and waiting for us to engage.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater to Salt: Navigating the Tides of Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:10:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve trotted from the crystal-clear streams of the Rockies to the azure expanses of the Caribbean, I’ve learned one hard truth: the transition from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing is no mere step; it&amp;rsquo;s a leap across the threshold of two worlds. With each cast, you feel the salt in the air and the pulse of the ocean beneath your feet, and while the tactics may shift, the thrill is a constant. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a freshwater veteran dipping your toes into the salt or a rookie who can’t shake the itch to explore, the skills you’ve honed can be your passport to adventure in the briny deep.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Getting Hooked: The Essential Gear and Techniques for Saltwater Fly Fishing Newbies</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 06:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-02-the-art-of-saltwater-fly-fishing-gear-and-techniqu/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Saltwater fly fishing can feel like a rite of passage for many anglers, but for newbies, it’s often a confusing mix of excitement and intimidation. These guys on Reddit are figuring it out in real-time, discussing everything from the right gear to techniques that help bridge the gap between the shore and the fish. If you&amp;rsquo;re diving into the salty depths for the first time, there’s a world of information tucked into their stories—and a few hard-learned lessons to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater Newbie to Saltwater Sage: Navigating the Flats</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:06:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-saltwater-adventures-from-newbie-to-angler-on-the-/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Every saltwater angler can recall the moment when they first stepped onto the glistening flats, the sun warming their shoulders and the smell of the ocean mingling with the adrenaline of the chase. Transitioning from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing can feel like stepping into a different world, and it’s a journey that’s both daunting and exhilarating. Whether you’re a newbie casting for the first time, like the enthusiastic angler who recently shared their experience in La Paz, or you&amp;rsquo;re gearing up with a trusty 9-foot rod and chartreuse fly, the saltwater bug is contagious.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saltwater Fly Fishing: From the Flats to the Deep Blue</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:08:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-saltwater-adventures-from-flats-to-blue-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that this realm offers a diverse tapestry of adventures, techniques, and gear. From the bustling flats teeming with bonefish and permit to the vast blue waters where mighty tarpon roam, our experiences remind us that every angler can find their niche in the salt. A recent Reddit post highlighted the thrill of a first-time outing in La Paz, where the excitement of live bait and fast retrieves turned a casual day into a memorable adventure. Similarly, tales of epic tarpon days in Costa Rica serve as a testament to the sheer adrenaline and joy these fish can bring to our lines.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing Silver Dreams: The Allure of Saltwater Fly Fishing Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-exploring-saltwater-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 09:32:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-exploring-saltwater-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Ah, that unmistakable thrill when the sun-kissed horizon meets the shimmering surface of the ocean. Saltwater fly fishing is not just about the catch; it&amp;rsquo;s an adventure steeped in the salty breeze and the promise of epic battles against nature&amp;rsquo;s finest. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re casting a line in the tropical shallows of La Paz or the wild coasts of Costa Rica, each location offers a unique canvas for your fishing story. Fresh reports from fellow anglers remind us that every cast can lead to both mistakes and triumphs, and it’s in those moments that we discover what it truly means to be a saltwater fly fisherman.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Grand Slam: Mastering the Saltwater Flats Experience</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel the thrill that comes with targeting species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit—collectively known as the Grand Slam. Our exploration of this unique fishing environment, from the stunning flats of La Paz to Costa Rica&amp;rsquo;s rich waters, showcases techniques that not only enhance our skills but also deepen our appreciation for the sport. Anglers everywhere are discovering that the saltwater experience is about much more than just the catch; it&amp;rsquo;s about embracing the vibrant ecosystems and the sheer unpredictability of the ocean&amp;rsquo;s offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing Silver Kings: Our Guide to Tarpon Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of tarpon fishing, we find ourselves captivated by the incredible stories and insights shared by fellow anglers. From the thrill of battling the &amp;lsquo;silver king&amp;rsquo; in Costa Rica to the humbling experience of learning on the beach with a simple fly rod, the journey of targeting tarpon is one filled with highs and lows that unite us all as fishermen. In one Reddit post, a seasoned angler shares the joys of what they call a &amp;lsquo;giant tarpon day,&amp;rsquo; while another recounts their rookie experience that sparked an unquenchable thirst for saltwater fishing. These narratives remind us that every great angler starts somewhere, and it&amp;rsquo;s the pursuit of these majestic fish that binds our community together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Waters and Fisheries</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we are not just participants in a sport; we are stewards of our waters. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight pressing conservation issues across various regions, reminding us that our fishing experiences are deeply intertwined with the health of aquatic ecosystems. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at revitalizing trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that the fight for our fisheries is both complex and critical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Flats: Saltwater Fly Fishing Techniques and Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-saltwater-adventures-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the flats present both unique challenges and unforgettable rewards. From the adrenaline rush of landing a giant tarpon in Costa Rica to the strategic nuances of targeting bonefish and permit, our exploration of these articles reveals the depth of skill and knowledge required to truly excel in saltwater environments. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a seasoned angler or just wading into the world of saltwater fly fishing, there’s a wealth of insights to glean from the experiences shared by fellow anglers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Big Ones: A Saltwater Fly Fishing Odyssey</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-saltwater-adventures-chasing-the-big-ones/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, it’s clear that the pursuit of species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit offers both challenge and thrill. From firsthand accounts of rookie anglers navigating the beaches of La Paz to the latest gear revelations from Sage, we’re reminded that every cast can lead to a story worth telling. This isn’t just about hooking the big one; it’s about the journey we embark on and the lessons learned along the way.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>There are good days... and then there are giant Tarpon days 😎🇨🇷🇨🇷</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 09:27:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qlrewl"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flyfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Saltwater bug</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:49:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</guid><description>Got my birthday present a little early. Headed out to the beach today. Make no mistake, I am as newbie as they come but I just couldn’t stay out of the water. 9ft rod, 9line, rio saltwater leader…just used the chartreuse fly today. Looked like a fool for the first 30 mins, but got to feeling it after that. Had one hit and miss but that feeling.</description></item><item><title>Sage Unveils Limited Edition Enforcer Grand Slam Reels: A Collector’s Dream for Flats Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Jan 2026 12:00:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-17-sage-unveils-limited-edition-enforcer-grand-slam-reels-a-col/</guid><description>The three-model collection pays tribute to the legendary saltwater &amp;ldquo;Grand Slam&amp;rdquo;—the rare feat of landing a bonefish, permit, and tarpon in a single day.</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Trout, Tarpon, and Other Critters in Costa Rica, with Kevin Jackson</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</guid><description>Did you know you can catch trout and tarpon in the same trip, along with exotic jungle species? I didn&amp;rsquo;t either, but Kevin Jackson [42:22] of Fly Fish Costa Rica shares&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>