<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Trout on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/trout/</link><description>Recent content in Trout on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/trout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Navigating the Waters of Trout Conservation: New Regulations and Their Impact</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-trout-conservation-navigating-new-regulations/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-trout-conservation-navigating-new-regulations/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers passionate about trout fishing, we understand the fine balance between enjoying our sport and ensuring the sustainability of trout populations. Recent articles shed light on critical developments in trout conservation efforts across the U.S., particularly with new regulations in Arkansas and the precarious status of the Skagit steelhead season. These changes not only affect our fishing practices but also require us to rethink our approach to conservation at large.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Fly Tying Fundamentals: Mastering Seasonal Patterns for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:07:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-fly-tying-fundamentals-patterns-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the essentials of fly tying, we recognize that the art is not just about creativity—it&amp;rsquo;s about understanding the rhythms of nature and how our patterns can mimic them. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a novice just starting out or an experienced tyer looking to refine your skills, the three classic flies highlighted by Bob Reece—Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis—serve as foundational tools in our fly boxes. These patterns don’t just represent the basics; they embody the versatility and adaptability required across seasons and conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Master the Streamer Game: Presentation Techniques for Serious Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-mastering-streamer-strategies-the-art-of-presentat/</link><pubDate>Sat, 31 Jan 2026 06:06:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-31-mastering-streamer-strategies-the-art-of-presentat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of streamer fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that our success hinges not just on the fly patterns we choose but primarily on how we present them. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight various techniques and insights that can elevate our fishing game, especially as we transition into the fall months when aggressive trout are on the hunt. From understanding the nuances of our retrieves to adapting our leader lengths and line types, mastering presentation is crucial for enticing those big bites.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Aquatic Heritage</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:12:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers and stewards of our waterways, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial that we stay informed and engaged with the pressing conservation issues affecting our favorite fishing spots. From the new regulations in Arkansas aimed at reviving trout populations to the looming threat of industrial mining in Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s pristine Boundary Waters, the conversation around conservation has never been more urgent. These issues are not isolated; they are interconnected and reflect broader challenges we face in protecting our ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Streamers Unleashed: Mastering the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-mastering-streamer-techniques-the-art-of-presentat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:11:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-mastering-streamer-techniques-the-art-of-presentat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, the difference between a good day on the water and a legendary one often boils down to presentation. As we dive into the nuances of this technique, we find that factors like leader length, line choice, and the rhythm of our retrieves can dramatically influence our success. Articles like &amp;lsquo;Fishing Streamers Is Still All About Presentation&amp;rsquo; remind us that whether we’re using a classic Woolly Bugger or an intricate articulated pattern, it’s the dance of the fly in the water that truly entices those aggressive trout.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Strategies for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we navigate the diverse seasons of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to adapt our techniques to the ever-changing behaviors of these spirited fish. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall to the subtle nuances of spring creeks, understanding the seasonal dynamics can significantly enhance our angling success. In this roundup, we draw insights from various articles that highlight pivotal strategies for each season, ensuring we&amp;rsquo;re well-equipped to tackle trout no matter the month.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Change: Navigating Conservation Challenges in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that our passion for fishing is deeply intertwined with the health of our ecosystems. Recent developments across various regions remind us that while we cast our lines, we must also cast our voices in support of conservation efforts. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at recovering trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, the fishing landscape is at a critical juncture. Each of these stories illustrates the complexities of balancing our love for the sport with the urgent need to protect our freshwater resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamer Presentation: The Key to Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:48:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to streamer fishing, the nuances of presentation can make all the difference between a day of casting and a day of catching. As we&amp;rsquo;ve seen in various discussions—from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline’s insights on the art of streamer movement to Reddit’s lively exchanges about effective patterns—our approach to how we present our flies can be the game-changer. Whether we’re working with articulated patterns or classic sculpin imitations, it’s clear that finesse in our technique is paramount. The water is alive with potential, and it’s our job to entice those fish with the right moves.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout: Seasonal Techniques for Year-Round Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:31:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-trout-fishing-techniques-for-every-season/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we journey through the seasons, our approach to trout fishing must evolve alongside the changing conditions. From the aggressive feeding patterns of fall trout, as detailed by Bob Reece at Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline, to the vital implications of weather patterns outlined by Fly Lords, we gain a clearer understanding of how to adapt our strategies effectively. We’re reminded that staying attuned to environmental cues not only enhances our success but also deepens our connection to the water we love to fish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Strategies for Hooking Big Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:29:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-mastering-streamer-strategies-for-trout/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of streamer fishing, it becomes evident that success isn’t just a matter of tossing a big fly into the water and hoping for the best. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight a critical theme: the importance of presentation. From the insights shared in Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline about using a long leader and intermediate line to bring your sculpin patterns to life, to the discussion on the deliberate retrieves necessary for patterns like Woolly Buggers, we see that the way our flies behave can make all the difference. Whether we’re fishing in a tailwater or a fast-moving stream, mastering these nuanced techniques can elevate our fishing game substantially.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Fly Tying: The Essential Patterns Every Angler Should Know</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-fly-tying-fundamentals-crafting-your-own-success/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we take a deep dive into the fundamentals of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few foundational patterns can unlock a world of fishing success. From Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s insights in &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers,&amp;rsquo; we learn that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just go-to flies; they are stepping stones to understanding the craft. Each of these flies encapsulates essential techniques that every aspiring tier should grasp, laying the groundwork for more complex creations down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Tomorrow: The Crucial Role of Conservation in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As passionate anglers, we know that our sport is inseparable from the health of our ecosystems. Recent articles highlight a growing awareness of conservation issues that directly impact our fishing experiences and the future of fish populations. From Arkansas&amp;rsquo; new trout regulations in the wake of a hatchery crisis to the alarming potential threats facing Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s Boundary Waters, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we must prioritize conservation efforts like never before. These discussions are not just policy debates; they are calls to action for us as stewards of the waters we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Trout Techniques: From Seasonal Strategies to Catching Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-trout-techniques-from-hatches-to-catch/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the world of trout fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that our approach must evolve with the seasons. From the new regulations impacting the White River system to the nuanced techniques required for catching trout during the colder months, we are reminded that adaptability is key to our success on the water. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered showcase not just the challenges we face in maintaining sustainable fish populations, but also the artistry and strategy involved in maximizing our catch rates throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering Streamers: Unleashing the Art of Presentation for Trophy Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:57:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-streamers-the-art-of-presentation/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to fly fishing for big trout, mastering the art of streamer presentation is non-negotiable. We’ve gathered insights from seasoned anglers and experts who emphasize that how we present our streamers can make all the difference between a day of empty casts and a net full of trophies. Whether you’re working articulated patterns or classic styles, it’s clear that the magic lies in the dance of the fly through the water. Articles from Gink &amp;amp; Gasoline and contributions from the fly-tying community highlight techniques and strategies that can elevate our game, especially as we head into the fall months when trout become more aggressive.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Arkansas Implements New Trout Regulations Following Historic Hatchery Crisis</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</guid><description>The new rules, effective February 1, 2026, replace the emergency catch-and-release orders enacted in October 2025 and signal cautious optimism that the White River system can sustain limited harvest while its fish populations recover.</description></item><item><title>Is this a rainbow?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-this-a-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:13:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-this-a-rainbow/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/4bdukvxevkfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/troutfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>One of my biggest accomplishments yet</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 11:56:46 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-one-of-my-biggest-accomplishments-yet/</guid><description>One of my biggest accomplishments so far, the California heritage trout challenge. Fort the first trout, I went up to the Tahoe area to catch the Lahontan cutthrot trout.</description></item><item><title>Fishing Streamers Is Still All About Presentation</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-fishing-streamers-is-still-all-about-presentation/</guid><description>Mastering the art of streamer fishing hinges on presentation—something every fly angler can appreciate, whether you’re tossing a hefty articulated pattern or a classic Maine-style streamer. In a recent outing on a prime Tailwater, I found success working snaky sculpins with a long leader and intermediate line, while my friends experimented with a Sex Dungeon and other variations, proving that it&amp;rsquo;s all about how you make that imitation dance through the water. Tight lines and rising fish await those willing to perfect their technique; dive into the full article for tips on maximizing your streamer game!</description></item><item><title>The Fragile Ecosystem: Conservation Challenges Facing Fly Fishing Today</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we revel in the thrill of casting our lines into pristine waters, yet we must remain vigilant about the environmental challenges that threaten our beloved sport. Recent articles shed light on pressing conservation issues, from the alarming &amp;lsquo;snow drought&amp;rsquo; affecting Western rivers to the bureaucratic hurdles endangering the iconic Skagit River steelhead season. These challenges not only impact our fishing experiences but also the health of our aquatic ecosystems and the future of fish populations we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Mastering the Art of Fly Tying: Essential Patterns and Techniques for Every Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:47:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-essentials-of-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we immerse ourselves in the essential craft of fly tying, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that mastering a few key patterns can lay a solid foundation for our fishing success. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re new to the vice or looking to refine your skills, articles like Bob Reece&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;3 Classic Flies For New Tyers&amp;rsquo; remind us that the Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail, and Elk Hair Caddis are not just staples; they are stepping stones into the broader world of fly tying. These flies offer us the chance to practice crucial techniques, from tying stability to creating lifelike movements in the water.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Roadkill Streamers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:05:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-roadkill-streamers/</guid><description>If you want to target hefty trout, forget the small stuff—streamers are your ticket to tight lines, accounting for a staggering 42% of four-pound fish caught in Livingston, Montana. Patterns like Woolly Buggers and Bitch Creeks can dominate in fast water, especially when you employ a slow, deliberate retrieve to mimic injured prey. Don’t miss the chance to amp up your streamer game and hook into those rising fish; the water’s waiting for your next cast!</description></item><item><title>Trout Tactics: Mastering the Art and Science of Freshwater Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:05:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-trout-tactics-mastering-the-freshwater-game/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive deeper into the world of trout fishing, we recognize that the pursuit of these elusive fish goes far beyond simply casting a line. From experimenting with unconventional bait, as seen in the Reddit post where a wacky rigged trout worm led to a successful catch, to understanding the body language of aggressive trout in fall, our journey is filled with insights that can elevate our angling game. We’re not just fishing; we’re learning to communicate with the fish in their own language—be it through the right flies or the perfect presentation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>No winter storm in NM</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</guid><description>Hand tied small streamer deaddrifted under indicator tore up. Stockers.</description></item><item><title>Nice stocked Rainbow</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 19:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-nice-stocked-rainbow/</guid><description>Was throwing lures all morning with no follows or hits. Tried something a bit unconventional and was able to hook into this one with two trout worms wacky rigged on a trout magnet jig under a bobber. Close to 15 inches.</description></item><item><title>First ever Rainbow Trout!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-ever-rainbow-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:44:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-ever-rainbow-trout/</guid><description>Caught my first rainbow trout ever in a stocked pond in Louisiana! Really cool that LDWF does it for the communities. Beautiful fish and a fun fight, can’t wait to catch more later this year in Colorado.</description></item><item><title>Sea trout muddler</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-sea-trout-muddler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 10:39:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-sea-trout-muddler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/b2potzw23cfg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reading The Body Language of Highly Aggressive Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move into the fall months, the use of streamer patterns typically increases for many fly fishers. There are many factors that lead to success when pursuing trout with these beefy creations. Evaluating the body language of the aggressive fish that chase these flies can improve your odds of hooking up.</description></item><item><title>Never seen one like this.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-never-seen-one-like-this/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 07:13:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-never-seen-one-like-this/</guid><description>My little brother caught this trout at Lake Siskiyou, CA. Is this a rainbow?</description></item><item><title>First 2 of the year</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-first-2-of-the-year/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 19:20:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-first-2-of-the-year/</guid><description>Located in Ohio, and although I have been trying, I haven’t been able to catch anything since New Year’s Eve. Today I decided to ditch work early, and hit the trout honey hole. No keepers, but was happy to end my drought, and get my first of the year.</description></item><item><title>Stocked rainbow. Learning to use kastmasters and spoons more.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-stocked-rainbow-learning-to-use-kastmasters-and-spoons-more/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:16:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-stocked-rainbow-learning-to-use-kastmasters-and-spoons-more/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://i.redd.it/xv57p57q77fg1.jpeg"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/troutfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can you help me identify this trout is it wild or stocked</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</guid><description>Caught in bishop Ca catch and release</description></item><item><title>“Snow Drought” Threatening Western Rivers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-snow-drought-threatening-western-rivers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 16:41:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-snow-drought-threatening-western-rivers/</guid><description>An aptly-named “snow drought” has much of the Western United States in its grasp, threatening water supplies in reservoirs, and flows in many of the country’s favorite trout rivers. A quick glance at the National Weather and Climate Center’s snow-water equivalent map paints a stark picture.</description></item><item><title>New Spinners I've Always Wanted To Try.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-new-spinners-i-ve-always-wanted-to-try/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 12:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-new-spinners-i-ve-always-wanted-to-try/</guid><description>I have high hopes for these and can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see if they will contend against Mepps, Panther Martin, and Rooster Tails. I will be targeting stocked trout, so it should be fun.</description></item><item><title>Another “tico” trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-another-tico-trout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 09:53:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-another-tico-trout/</guid><description>One of the few “big” trouts we have here in Costa Rica, it’s not that common to find them this size</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Some wild Utah cutthroat</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-some-wild-utah-cutthroat/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:47:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-some-wild-utah-cutthroat/</guid><description>My first fish of the new year, I had never thrown my bladed jigs for trout for some reason and decided to try it out. I went to hit my favorite spot and discovered that it was now posted no trespassing.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Essential Winter Midges and Technical Nymphs</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</guid><description>When winter temperatures settle in, trout slow down—and so must our approach. Success demands technical midge patterns and refined subsurface presentations that can fool even the most lethargic fish.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Golden Trout, with Jessica Strickland</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:04:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</guid><description>Jessica Strickland [38:07]is Trout Unlimited&amp;rsquo;s California Inland Trout director and is an expert on the historical and curent range&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>