<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Fly-Fishing on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/fly-fishing/</link><description>Recent content in Fly-Fishing on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:09:25 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/fly-fishing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>❄️Waiting to ride. Here are some of my favorite terrestrials. With Carl’s Cicada’s, a sneaky presentation is key. False cast just behind the fish for aim. Then, cast just ahead of the fish at a 45° angle. Let it drift a bit and then retrieve swiftly but slowly across the fish’s nose. 10/10 🎣</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-waiting-to-ride-here-are-some-of-my-favorite-terrestrials-wi/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 06:09:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-waiting-to-ride-here-are-some-of-my-favorite-terrestrials-wi/</guid><description>Read more about ❄️Waiting to ride. Here are some of my favorite terrestrials. With Carl’s Cicada’s, a sneaky presentation is key. False cast just behind the fish for aim. Then, cast just ahead of the fish at a 45° angle. Let it drift a bit and then retrieve swiftly but slowly across the fish’s nose. 10/10 🎣.</description></item><item><title>Euro nymphing rod for dry flies?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-euro-nymphing-rod-for-dry-flies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 05:43:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-euro-nymphing-rod-for-dry-flies/</guid><description>I recently ordered a diamondback gen 4 online. The more I’m researching, it almost seems as though it could be viable as a dry fly rod as well. Is this true? If so, what qualities that a euro rod have that cross over into a dry fly rod? I purchase a 10’7”3wt. I know that there’s no “rules” but I want some opinions and knowledge.</description></item><item><title>Winter trout spey</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-winter-trout-spey/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Feb 2026 02:19:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-21-winter-trout-spey/</guid><description>First 2 pics are of the same fish</description></item><item><title>Icelandic sheep streamer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-icelandic-sheep-streamer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:13:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-icelandic-sheep-streamer/</guid><description>First time trying this out. Sheep tail, laser dub head, covered in solarez, tied on ahrex minnow hook</description></item><item><title>Some more wild trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-some-more-wild-trout/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 20:00:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-some-more-wild-trout/</guid><description>Read more about Some more wild trout.</description></item><item><title>My first salmon</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-my-first-salmon/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:51:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-my-first-salmon/</guid><description>Yes I know it&amp;rsquo;s a kelt but it put up a real fight and I&amp;rsquo;m still really happy. Got it on a hand tied black-red-yellow tube fly. 13lbs.</description></item><item><title>Fly Fishing 101: How To Choose Your First Fly Rod</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 15:29:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-fly-fishing-101-how-to-choose-your-first-fly-rod/</guid><description>Walk into any fly shop, or browse around online, and you’ll quickly realize there are more fly rod choices out there than questionable food at a casino buffet. In this case, though, picking a less-than-stellar rod won’t give you food poisoning, so there’s a lot less risk involved.</description></item><item><title>Taming Marabou Tails</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-taming-marabou-tails/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move toward spring, the presentation of streamers increases for many fly fishers. For those of us that tie our own, the use of some materials is far more common than others. Marabou tends to be one of those materials, particularly in the tails of many bugger style streamers.</description></item><item><title>First Two Flies</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-first-two-flies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 07:24:01 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-first-two-flies/</guid><description>New to fly tying, these are the 1st two I&amp;rsquo;ve tried</description></item><item><title>Rising streamers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-rising-streamers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 04:29:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-20-rising-streamers/</guid><description>Been getting lots of follows but there always turning off it when the weighted streamer drops. So little foam front guy lifts on the pause and the fish approve. Also kicks side to side really nice. Size 4</description></item><item><title>Chile 🇨🇱 brown trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-chile-brown-trout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 22:59:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-chile-brown-trout/</guid><description>Just a few highlights from a great couple of days fishing in the south of Chile! I’ve been in Santiago for a couple of months while I’m studying abroad and knew I had to make the trip down south while I had a good chance. Definitely don’t regret it.</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Fall, What You Should Know About Sinking Fly Lines</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-fishing-the-fall-what-you-should-know-about-sinking-fly-line/</guid><description>By Garner Reid A GOOD PORTION OF MY FLY FISHING INVOLVES THROWING SOME SORT OF A SINKING FLY LINE. Realistically, half of my time on the water involves streamers and sinking lines at least for some part of the day. If I am not out on the water guiding for streamer-eating fish like stripers, I’m in the fly shop talking about them.</description></item><item><title>How to Tie: The Red Tag Nymph</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Feb 2026 02:48:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-19-how-to-tie-the-red-tag-nymph/</guid><description>In this week’s “How to Tie” feature, APH Flying Tying shows us a fantastic attractor pattern you can fish all year long, the Red Tag Nymph.</description></item><item><title>Boundary Waters Protection with Matthew Schultz, Fishing Guides’ Favorite Beer Test, and More | TWIFF – Flylords Podcast</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 21:14:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-boundary-waters-protection-with-matthew-schultz-fishing-guid/</guid><description>Follow along as we explore the latest fly fishing news and controversial opinions in This Week in Fly Fishing with Jared and Wills. In this episode, Matthew Schultz with Sportsmen for the Boundary Waters joins the crew to talk about the concerning conservation issues the Boundary Waters are facing.</description></item><item><title>Yellowstone To Open Fishing Season Early</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-yellowstone-to-open-fishing-season-early/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 15:00:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-yellowstone-to-open-fishing-season-early/</guid><description>Yellowstone National Park’s fly fishing season has, for years, opened on the Saturday of Memorial Day Weekend. That opening date will be moved back to May 1, 2026, for three rivers inside the park.</description></item><item><title>Fly Fishing: Our Trout Rivers and Streams Need More Wood</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-fly-fishing-our-trout-rivers-and-streams-need-more-wood/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-18-fly-fishing-our-trout-rivers-and-streams-need-more-wood/</guid><description>Several years back, one of my favorite wild trout streams, only a few miles from my house, got slammed with tornados and high winds (from back to back hurricanes that had moved up from Florida). The aftermath from the strong storms, downed dozens, upon dozens of trees along the stream.</description></item><item><title>DENVER FLY FISHING SHOW: NEW PRODUCTS OF 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-denver-fly-fishing-show-new-products-of-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:31:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-denver-fly-fishing-show-new-products-of-2026/</guid><description>Each winter, brands bring new and updated gear to the Denver Fly Fishing Show. It’s a chance to see what’s changing, what’s being refined, and what products are making their way into anglers’ hands in the coming season.</description></item><item><title>Florida Sportsman - March 2026</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-florida-sportsman-march-2026/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 15:00:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-florida-sportsman-march-2026/</guid><description>Florida Sportsman is known well for featuring articles on all types of fishing, ranging from fly fishing and other types of inshore angling to fishing done in deeper ocean waters. These articles inform the magazines readers on what types of fish are in season…</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Streamers, Nymphs, and Innovative Emergers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-tying-tuesday-streamers-nymphs-and-innovative-emergers/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 12:00:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-tying-tuesday-streamers-nymphs-and-innovative-emergers/</guid><description>From the streamer junkie stripping heavy articulated meat to the technical purist, there’s something here to keep your hands busy and your mind on the water. So heat up the coffee, fire up the UV lamp, and put a few new tools in the box before spring arrives.</description></item><item><title>Last Cast Bonefish</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-last-cast-bonefish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-17-last-cast-bonefish/</guid><description>Bonefishing, for me, is the purest form of the drug. I’m just returning from the first of three G&amp;amp;G Bonefish Schools in the Bahamas. This trip was more of a reunion than a school, with better than half of the anglers returning for the second or third time.</description></item><item><title>Fast Pocket Water &amp; Big Attractor Dry Flies</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-fast-pocket-water-big-attractor-dry-flies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2026 08:58:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-02-16-fast-pocket-water-big-attractor-dry-flies/</guid><description>During the spring, summer and fall I often get the itch to forget about catching numbers and instead see how big of an attractor dry fly I can get away with fishing and still fool trout. For those of you who don&amp;rsquo;t know, my closest trout waters are North Georgia and Western North Carolina.</description></item><item><title>Wanderlust on the Water: Unveiling the World's Hidden Fly Fishing Gems</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-traveling-the-world-unique-fly-fishing-destination/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:09:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-traveling-the-world-unique-fly-fishing-destination/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As the sun rises on another day of casting lines, the thrill of discovering new fishing destinations pulses through my veins like the salty air of the Florida Keys. Whether it’s the allure of Mongolia’s untamed wilderness, the breathtaking heights of the Alps, or the vibrant jungles of Costa Rica, each location beckons with the promise of adventure and diversity in species. It’s time to pack your gear and shake off the familiar, as I dive into some of the most unique fly fishing spots around the globe.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Freshwater to Salt: Navigating the Tides of Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2026 08:10:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-04-from-freshwater-to-salt-transitioning-your-fly-fis/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I’ve trotted from the crystal-clear streams of the Rockies to the azure expanses of the Caribbean, I’ve learned one hard truth: the transition from freshwater to saltwater fly fishing is no mere step; it&amp;rsquo;s a leap across the threshold of two worlds. With each cast, you feel the salt in the air and the pulse of the ocean beneath your feet, and while the tactics may shift, the thrill is a constant. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a freshwater veteran dipping your toes into the salt or a rookie who can’t shake the itch to explore, the skills you’ve honed can be your passport to adventure in the briny deep.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing the Grand Slam: Mastering the Saltwater Flats Experience</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Jan 2026 06:12:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-30-the-saltwater-experience-fishing-the-flats/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of saltwater fly fishing, we can&amp;rsquo;t help but feel the thrill that comes with targeting species like tarpon, bonefish, and permit—collectively known as the Grand Slam. Our exploration of this unique fishing environment, from the stunning flats of La Paz to Costa Rica&amp;rsquo;s rich waters, showcases techniques that not only enhance our skills but also deepen our appreciation for the sport. Anglers everywhere are discovering that the saltwater experience is about much more than just the catch; it&amp;rsquo;s about embracing the vibrant ecosystems and the sheer unpredictability of the ocean&amp;rsquo;s offerings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Chasing Silver Kings: Our Guide to Tarpon Adventures</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:50:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-saltwater-adventures-targeting-tarpon/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the exhilarating world of tarpon fishing, we find ourselves captivated by the incredible stories and insights shared by fellow anglers. From the thrill of battling the &amp;lsquo;silver king&amp;rsquo; in Costa Rica to the humbling experience of learning on the beach with a simple fly rod, the journey of targeting tarpon is one filled with highs and lows that unite us all as fishermen. In one Reddit post, a seasoned angler shares the joys of what they call a &amp;lsquo;giant tarpon day,&amp;rsquo; while another recounts their rookie experience that sparked an unquenchable thirst for saltwater fishing. These narratives remind us that every great angler starts somewhere, and it&amp;rsquo;s the pursuit of these majestic fish that binds our community together.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Essential Fly Fishing Gear: The Must-Haves for Every Angler's Arsenal</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-fly-fishing-gear-essentials-what-you-need/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-fly-fishing-gear-essentials-what-you-need/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we dive into the world of fly fishing gear, it’s clear that having the right equipment can make all the difference on the water. From the latest innovations in rods like the Orvis Recon to specialized reels like Sage&amp;rsquo;s Enforcer Grand Slam, our gear choices play a pivotal role in our fishing success. Each piece of gear not only enhances our experience but also reflects our personal style and fishing goals. Whether we’re targeting freshwater trout or saltwater species, understanding the essentials ensures we&amp;rsquo;re prepared for whatever the day brings.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gear Up: Must-Have Equipment for the Modern Angler</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-essential-equipment-for-every-angler/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:59:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-essential-equipment-for-every-angler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for another season of fishing, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to assess the tools at our disposal. Whether we&amp;rsquo;re seasoned veterans or newcomers to the sport, understanding the latest in fly fishing equipment can significantly enhance our experience on the water. From rods that offer unparalleled performance to gifts that every angler will appreciate, we’ve gathered insights from recent articles that highlight what we should consider for our next fishing adventure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Duane Hada Paints Memorial Mural Honoring Fly-Fishing Icon Dave Whitlock</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 18:28:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-duane-hada-paints-memorial-mural-honoring-fly-fishing-icon-d/</guid><description>Renowned Ozark artist Duane Hada is painting a memorial tribute to Dave Whitlock, the Oklahoma-born fly-fishing legend who spent more than four decades on the White River and whose innovations—from the ubiquitous Dave&amp;rsquo;s Hopper to the Whitlock-Vibert Box egg incubator system—helped establish north&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>New to streamers! lmk on opinions</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-new-to-streamers-lmk-on-opinions/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 16:16:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-new-to-streamers-lmk-on-opinions/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qmywpx"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>A streamer a day keeps the cold away!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-a-streamer-a-day-keeps-the-cold-away/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 13:38:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-a-streamer-a-day-keeps-the-cold-away/</guid><description>Hackle, flash, reverse tied craft fur coming in hot!</description></item><item><title>Is Original Artwork Allowed? Sci-Fi Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 12:38:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-is-original-artwork-allowed-sci-fi-fly-fishing/</guid><description>My friends told me to share some of my fly fishing related artwork here. I&amp;rsquo;m a local artist in the Helena, MT area and I create Sci-Fi based artwork that sometimes overlaps with fly fishing. Hope you all enjoy.</description></item><item><title>Pb grayling for me today!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-pb-grayling-for-me-today/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 10:23:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-pb-grayling-for-me-today/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qmp8lu"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flyfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Floating, fly fishing, and camping the Mongolian wilderness</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-floating-fly-fishing-and-camping-the-mongolian-wilderness/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 09:02:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-floating-fly-fishing-and-camping-the-mongolian-wilderness/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qmmzvn"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flyfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Gear Up: Elevate Your Fly Fishing Game with the Latest Must-Haves</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-the-best-fly-fishing-equipment/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:49:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-gear-up-the-best-fly-fishing-equipment/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for another season on the water, it’s crucial to stay informed about the latest advancements in fly fishing equipment. Recent discussions surrounding the new Orvis Recon rod have sparked a lively debate in our community. With its impressive blend of performance and affordability, it’s no wonder anglers are eager to see if this rod lives up to the hype. However, we should also reflect on the broader question: do we sometimes place too much importance on the gear itself? The Drift article reminds us that while top-tier rods can enhance our experience, the joy of fly fishing ultimately comes from our connection to the water and the fish we pursue.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Essential Gear Guide: Equip Yourself for Fly Fishing Success</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-gear-up-the-essentials-for-every-angler/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:06:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-gear-up-the-essentials-for-every-angler/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As we gear up for our next fishing adventure, it’s crucial to ensure we have the right tools at our disposal. From protective eyewear to reliable rods, our gear can make or break the experience on the water. In this roundup, we delve into the must-haves every fly angler should consider, drawing insights from fellow anglers who have shared their favorite essentials. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a novice casting your first line or a seasoned pro refining your setup, there’s something here for everyone looking to elevate their fishing game.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>No winter storm in NM</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 20:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-no-winter-storm-in-nm/</guid><description>Hand tied small streamer deaddrifted under indicator tore up. Stockers.</description></item><item><title>2 months into fly tying.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-2-months-into-fly-tying/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 16:21:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-2-months-into-fly-tying/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qm2c4p"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flytying&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>First fly since 1993, and it's ugly.</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 14:11:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-fly-since-1993-and-it-s-ugly/</guid><description>Got bored and had access to a while bunch of fly tying supplies. Figured I should likely have a concept of it being the local fly club president. haven&amp;rsquo;t tied a fly since 1993 at the Scout jamboree. seems to have turned out fine, not sure if it would survive a cast. Not sure what it&amp;rsquo;s for.</description></item><item><title>First time fly fishing in the salt</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:52:10 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-first-time-fly-fishing-in-the-salt/</guid><description>Just came back from La Paz BCS. Hired a guide in Ensenada de Muertos for some fishing. We trolled lures for a few hours then Capt said change of plan and we hit the beach inside the lighthouse. He threw live sardines to get them frenzied and I cast into the fray, tuck the rod under my arm and two hand retrieve fast.</description></item><item><title>My Favorite Fishing Sunglasses (Sanofan Fluid Tint)</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 11:27:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-my-favorite-fishing-sunglasses-sanofan-fluid-tint/</guid><description>I’ve replied to a couple of posts in this sub with my recommendation for the best fly fishing sunglasses I’ve ever used, so I figure I’d make a post about these. These Sanofan Fluid Tints are not only the best value for money fishing sunnies I’ve ever seen, but just downright the best I’ve ever used (mauis, smiths, etc).</description></item><item><title>There are good days... and then there are giant Tarpon days 😎🇨🇷🇨🇷</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 09:27:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-there-are-good-days-and-then-there-are-giant-tarpon-days/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/gallery/1qlrewl"&gt;Read the full article at Reddit r/flyfishing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reading The Body Language of Highly Aggressive Trout</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 08:58:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-reading-the-body-language-of-highly-aggressive-trout/</guid><description>By Bob Reece As we move into the fall months, the use of streamer patterns typically increases for many fly fishers. There are many factors that lead to success when pursuing trout with these beefy creations. Evaluating the body language of the aggressive fish that chase these flies can improve your odds of hooking up.</description></item><item><title>Winter Project</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-winter-project/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 05:45:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-24-winter-project/</guid><description>My fly tying season pretty much wrapped up. What started as &amp;ldquo;fill a few spaces in the boxes after last season&amp;rdquo; may have got slightly out of hand&amp;hellip;.</description></item><item><title>The Ultimate Fly Fishing Gift Guide [2026]</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-the-ultimate-fly-fishing-gift-guide-2026/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 21:00:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-the-ultimate-fly-fishing-gift-guide-2026/</guid><description>The Ultimate Fly Fishing Gift Guide for Any Angler Buying gifts for anglers can be a tricky task. Whether you’re a participant or unfamiliar with the sport, picking the perfect gift is often an intimidating and sometimes stressful endeavor, as each angler possesses a unique taste.</description></item><item><title>Saltwater bug</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 20:49:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-saltwater-bug/</guid><description>Got my birthday present a little early. Headed out to the beach today. Make no mistake, I am as newbie as they come but I just couldn’t stay out of the water. 9ft rod, 9line, rio saltwater leader…just used the chartreuse fly today. Looked like a fool for the first 30 mins, but got to feeling it after that. Had one hit and miss but that feeling.</description></item><item><title>3 Classic Flies For New Tyers</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 08:58:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-3-classic-flies-for-new-tyers/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Three points of contact provide stability. There are a plethora of patterns that new tiers could begin with. Yet three in particular lay out the fundamental techniques needed to create a stabile foundation for your fly tying future. The Woolly Bugger, Pheasant Tail and Elk Hair Caddis have all proven their worth.</description></item><item><title>Keep Your Hands on the Cork</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-22-keep-your-hands-on-the-cork/</guid><description>Like so many others out there, I&amp;rsquo;ve broken my fair share of fly rods over the years. I&amp;rsquo;ve slammed them in tailgates, stuck them in ceiling fans and I&amp;rsquo;ve squashed quite a few trying to get in and out of my cataraft to quickly.</description></item><item><title>2026 F3T Behind the Lens: The Jane Project: Carried by the Current</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-the-jane-project-carried-by-the-cur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 20:00:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-2026-f3t-behind-the-lens-the-jane-project-carried-by-the-cur/</guid><description>Fly fishing films often focus on exotic places, trophy fish, and the action-packed storytelling and adventure that anglers dream of. Yet every so often, a film that transcends the big-fish moments comes to life, sharing the deeper stories, individuals, and messages that can be overlooked.</description></item><item><title>Is the New Orvis Recon the Best Rod for the Money? Our Thoughts</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</guid><description>Orvis just announced the newest addition to its fly rod lineup, the redesigned Recon series. Since the release of the first Recon back in 2015, this rod has developed a huge following as a mid-priced, performance-driven fly rod.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Tying Tuesday: Essential Winter Midges and Technical Nymphs</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 11:00:50 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-tying-tuesday-essential-winter-midges-and-technical-nymphs/</guid><description>When winter temperatures settle in, trout slow down—and so must our approach. Success demands technical midge patterns and refined subsurface presentations that can fool even the most lethargic fish.</description></item><item><title>Rubber, Above &amp; Below</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</link><pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2026 08:58:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-20-rubber-above-below/</guid><description>By Bob Reece Round rubber and spandex are two members in the vast tide of synthetic materials that have washed over the fly tying world in recent years. They have both been used to create numerous surface and subsurface patterns. However, I would argue that one is better suited for the world above while the other thrives below.</description></item><item><title>The Drift: Do We Care Too Much About Fly Rods?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-the-drift-do-we-care-too-much-about-fly-rods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 19:43:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-the-drift-do-we-care-too-much-about-fly-rods/</guid><description>Last week, I wrote about my close encounter with a highly-collectible rod, the Winston 8’6″ 4-weight BIIt, nicknamed “The Staff of Moses.” I’m still kicking myself for not buying it (despite the $800+ price tag), but hopefully when the next one comes along, I’ll have some extra cash laying around.</description></item><item><title>What Current Fly Rods Will Be Collectibles In 20 Years?</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2026 18:22:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-16-what-current-fly-rods-will-be-collectibles-in-20-years/</guid><description>Some fly rods end up as more than just another entry in that year’s product catalog. A select few gain a cult following, often retaining their value (and exceeding their original retail price) as the years march on.</description></item><item><title>What the 2026 Snow Drought Means for Your Summer Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-15-what-the-2026-snow-drought-means-for-your-summer-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2026 14:34:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-15-what-the-2026-snow-drought-means-for-your-summer-fly-fishing/</guid><description>While late-season storms could still turn the tide, the current deficits would require what water managers call a &amp;ldquo;miracle March&amp;rdquo; to offset. For now, keep an eye on the gauges—but start forming your plan B.</description></item><item><title>Bahamas Fly Fishing Industry Leader Calls Out Government on Dormant Conservation Fund</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-12-bahamas-fly-fishing-industry-leader-calls-out-government-on-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:22:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-12-bahamas-fly-fishing-industry-leader-calls-out-government-on-/</guid><description>The president of the Bahamas Fly Fishing Industry Association is pushing back against what he calls government &amp;ldquo;lip service&amp;rdquo; toward protecting the country&amp;rsquo;s world-renowned flats fishery.</description></item><item><title>Meet the Nominees for the 2025 Orvis-Endorsed Awards!</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2025-03-03-meet-the-nominees-for-the-2025-orvis-endorsed-awards/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 16:49:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2025-03-03-meet-the-nominees-for-the-2025-orvis-endorsed-awards/</guid><description>2025 marks the 40th year that the Orvis Company will recognize excellence in sporting experiences through its Endorsed Lodges, Outfitters, and Guides (ELOG) program. The winners of this year’s coveted “Of the Year” Awards will be announced virtually via blog and social posts on March 26th. Here are this year’s nominees . .</description></item><item><title>How to get started in trout Spey with Pete Kutzer</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 19:53:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-25-how-to-get-started-in-trout-spey-with-pete-kutzer/</guid><description>Any kind of two-handed fishing is confusing for those of us who mostly fish with a single-handed rod. I asked the great Pete Kutzer&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Fishing the Alps, with Miha Ivanc</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-19-fishing-the-alps-with-miha-ivanc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 00:04:43 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-19-fishing-the-alps-with-miha-ivanc/</guid><description>I frequently get questions from listeners traveling to Europe, curious about fly fishing opportunities in Italy, France, Austria, and Switzerland. I&amp;rsquo;ve never fished there&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>The Elusive Golden Trout, with Jessica Strickland</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 01:04:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-13-the-elusive-golden-trout-with-jessica-strickland/</guid><description>Jessica Strickland [38:07]is Trout Unlimited&amp;rsquo;s California Inland Trout director and is an expert on the historical and curent range&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: 14 Tips for Spring Creek Fishing, with Brant Oswald</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-04-podcast-14-tips-for-spring-creek-fishing-with-brant-oswald/</guid><description>Brant Oswald [23:20] is a veteran guide, teacher, and fly shop operator with over 40 years in the business&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>THE GREAT AWAITS #4: Chilean Patagonia</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-01-the-great-awaits-4-chilean-patagonia/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 18:54:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-11-01-the-great-awaits-4-chilean-patagonia/</guid><description>Eduardo Barrueto was born an angler. Growing up in the small village of Balmaceda, in the eastern foothills of the Chilean Andes, he loved to fish with his father, a local schoolteacher. They would often hitchhike or take a bus to explore the region’s many . . .</description></item><item><title>So you want a job in the fly-fishing industry? With Kirk Deeter</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Oct 2024 16:47:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-28-so-you-want-a-job-in-the-fly-fishing-industry-with-kirk-deet/</guid><description>I get regular questions from people about getting a job in the fly-fishing industry, both in the podcast mailbox and in person at shows and store visits. It&amp;rsquo;s a tough question and I don&amp;rsquo;t have all the answers so I called upon my buddy Kirk Deeter&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>North American and European fly-tying cross pollination with Barry Ord Clarke</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 05:32:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-22-north-american-and-european-fly-tying-cross-pollination-with/</guid><description>Barry Ord Clarke is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s most popular fly tiers, through his books, videos, and web site. Originally from the UK but living in Norway, Barry keeps&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>Podcast: Trout, Tarpon, and Other Critters in Costa Rica, with Kevin Jackson</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 19:22:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2024-10-15-podcast-trout-tarpon-and-other-critters-in-costa-rica-with-k/</guid><description>Did you know you can catch trout and tarpon in the same trip, along with exotic jungle species? I didn&amp;rsquo;t either, but Kevin Jackson [42:22] of Fly Fish Costa Rica shares&amp;hellip;</description></item></channel></rss>