<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Regulations on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/regulations/</link><description>Recent content in Regulations on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:09:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/regulations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Casting for Change: The Crucial Role of Conservation in Fly Fishing's Future</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-the-intersection-of-fly-fishing-and-conservation-c/</link><pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2026 08:09:09 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-07-the-intersection-of-fly-fishing-and-conservation-c/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I pour over the latest developments in fly fishing and conservation, I can’t help but feel a blend of concern and optimism. The intersection of these two worlds is more critical than ever, as we grapple with pressing challenges that impact both our waterways and the fish that inhabit them. Recent articles shed light on regulatory shifts in Arkansas, threats to the Boundary Waters in Minnesota, and the stagnation of conservation funds in the Bahamas. Each of these issues not only highlights the fragility of our ecosystems but emphasizes the collective responsibility we carry as anglers to advocate for sustainable practices in our sport.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Navigating the Waters of Change: A Deep Dive into Trout Conservation Regulations</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-conservation-in-action-navigating-recent-trout-reg/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Feb 2026 07:07:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-02-01-conservation-in-action-navigating-recent-trout-reg/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As I wade through the currents of recent articles on trout conservation, a clear narrative emerges: collective fishing practices are at a pivotal juncture shaped by a combination of regulatory adjustments and ecological recovery efforts. From Arkansas&amp;rsquo;s proactive measures to revitalize the White River’s trout populations to the precarious state of Washington&amp;rsquo;s Skagit steelhead season, the future of our waterways is intricately tied to the decisions we make today. The fine balance between harvest and preservation has never been more critical, and as anglers, it’s our responsibility to stay informed and adaptable.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>