<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conservation on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</title><link>https://windknots.com/tags/conservation/</link><description>Recent content in Conservation on Windknots - Fishing News &amp; Stories</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:38 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://windknots.com/tags/conservation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Casting for Change: Navigating Conservation Challenges in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Jan 2026 17:49:38 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-29-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we know that our passion for fishing is deeply intertwined with the health of our ecosystems. Recent developments across various regions remind us that while we cast our lines, we must also cast our voices in support of conservation efforts. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at recovering trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, the fishing landscape is at a critical juncture. Each of these stories illustrates the complexities of balancing our love for the sport with the urgent need to protect our freshwater resources.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Conservation Conversations: Safeguarding Our Waters and Fisheries</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2026 13:30:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-28-conservation-conversations-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we are not just participants in a sport; we are stewards of our waters. The articles we&amp;rsquo;ve gathered highlight pressing conservation issues across various regions, reminding us that our fishing experiences are deeply intertwined with the health of aquatic ecosystems. From new regulations in Arkansas aimed at revitalizing trout populations to the legal battles surrounding the Snake River dams, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that the fight for our fisheries is both complex and critical.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Casting for Tomorrow: The Crucial Role of Conservation in Fly Fishing</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 19:58:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-the-importance-of-conservation-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As passionate anglers, we know that our sport is inseparable from the health of our ecosystems. Recent articles highlight a growing awareness of conservation issues that directly impact our fishing experiences and the future of fish populations. From Arkansas&amp;rsquo; new trout regulations in the wake of a hatchery crisis to the alarming potential threats facing Minnesota&amp;rsquo;s Boundary Waters, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that we must prioritize conservation efforts like never before. These discussions are not just policy debates; they are calls to action for us as stewards of the waters we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Arkansas Implements New Trout Regulations Following Historic Hatchery Crisis</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 17:48:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-25-arkansas-implements-new-trout-regulations-following-historic/</guid><description>The new rules, effective February 1, 2026, replace the emergency catch-and-release orders enacted in October 2025 and signal cautious optimism that the White River system can sustain limited harvest while its fish populations recover.</description></item><item><title>The Fragile Ecosystem: Conservation Challenges Facing Fly Fishing Today</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Jan 2026 07:48:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-25-conservation-challenges-in-fly-fishing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, we revel in the thrill of casting our lines into pristine waters, yet we must remain vigilant about the environmental challenges that threaten our beloved sport. Recent articles shed light on pressing conservation issues, from the alarming &amp;lsquo;snow drought&amp;rsquo; affecting Western rivers to the bureaucratic hurdles endangering the iconic Skagit River steelhead season. These challenges not only impact our fishing experiences but also the health of our aquatic ecosystems and the future of fish populations we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Protecting Our Waters: A Call to Action for Anglers</title><link>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-conservation-concerns-protecting-our-waters/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jan 2026 22:06:19 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/themes/2026-01-24-conservation-concerns-protecting-our-waters/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As anglers, our connection to the water goes beyond the simple joy of casting a line; it is intertwined with our responsibility to protect the ecosystems that sustain our favorite species. Recent discussions around conservation issues shed light on the critical challenges facing freshwater habitats and the fish that inhabit them. From the potential threat of industrial mining in the Boundary Waters to the uncertain future of the Skagit River’s steelhead season, the implications of these developments reach far beyond local waters. We must recognize that the health of our fisheries is inextricably linked to the political and environmental decisions made today.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Can you help me identify this trout is it wild or stocked</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Jan 2026 18:02:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-23-can-you-help-me-identify-this-trout-is-it-wild-or-stocked/</guid><description>Caught in bishop Ca catch and release</description></item><item><title>Is the New Orvis Recon the Best Rod for the Money? Our Thoughts</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 18:29:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-is-the-new-orvis-recon-the-best-rod-for-the-money-our-though/</guid><description>Orvis just announced the newest addition to its fly rod lineup, the redesigned Recon series. Since the release of the first Recon back in 2015, this rod has developed a huge following as a mid-priced, performance-driven fly rod.</description></item><item><title>Skagit River Steelhead Season Not Likely To Open</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-skagit-river-steelhead-season-not-likely-to-open/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 15:42:12 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-skagit-river-steelhead-season-not-likely-to-open/</guid><description>The late winter and early spring catch-and-release season on the famed Skagit River may not happen in 2026, and not because of too few wild steelhead returning to the river. In fact, the numbers support a limited catch-and-release fishery with no retention of wild fish allowed.</description></item><item><title>Flies That Catch Big Trout, The Truth Might Surprise You</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 08:58:26 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-21-flies-that-catch-big-trout-the-truth-might-surprise-you/</guid><description>I HAVE DEFINITE IDEAS ABOUT HOW TO CATCH BIG TROUT. APPARENTLY THEY ARE ALL WRONG. Like every other guy or gal with a fly rod, I have some pretty strong opinions about the kind of flies that catch big fish. These opinions are based on years of experience and experimentation.</description></item><item><title>Skagit Steelhead Season Hangs by a Thread—Not for Lack of Fish, But Funding</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2026 14:36:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-19-skagit-steelhead-season-hangs-by-a-thread-not-for-lack-of-fi/</guid><description>As of mid-January, the highly anticipated catch-and-release season on Washington&amp;rsquo;s Skagit and Sauk rivers—a bucket-list destination for steelhead anglers across the Pacific Northwest—stands on the verge of cancellation. The culprit isn&amp;rsquo;t biology. It&amp;rsquo;s bureaucracy.</description></item><item><title>Bahamas Fly Fishing Industry Leader Calls Out Government on Dormant Conservation Fund</title><link>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-12-bahamas-fly-fishing-industry-leader-calls-out-government-on-/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2026 18:22:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://windknots.com/articles/2026-01-12-bahamas-fly-fishing-industry-leader-calls-out-government-on-/</guid><description>The president of the Bahamas Fly Fishing Industry Association is pushing back against what he calls government &amp;ldquo;lip service&amp;rdquo; toward protecting the country&amp;rsquo;s world-renowned flats fishery.</description></item></channel></rss>